哇噻 兄弟
Whoa, Bro!
哇呜哇呜 呜呜呜
Wow! Wow! Oooo...
哈哈哈
Ha ha ha.
呜哇
Woot!
哈哈哈
Ha ha ha.
呕呜呜呜......
Oww...
呕呜......
Oww!...
呦
Yo!
当心！
Watch it!
你挡我路了 兄弟
You're in my way, bro.
噢 好吧
Oh, okay.
哇呜......
Wow...
Come on.
来吧
呜......
Oooo...
哈哈......
Haha...
我还行
I'm good.
是吗？ 你该飞得更快一些
You should be faster, huh?
哇 呜......
Wow! Oooo...
呕呜
Oww!
真酷啊 兄弟
It's cool, bro.
别那样 笨蛋 好嘛
Don't do that, coot.
咱们走吧
Let's go.
你很酷 我支持你 兄弟
It's cool. I'm with you, bro.
击掌
High-five.
嘿嘿
Hey, hey.
我得回去了 哥
I gotta get back, Bro.
老弟
Little bro.
走之前告诉我一件事
Tell me one thing before you go.
我是怎样死的
How did I die.
你中枪了
You got shot.
我们本可以逃的
We could have escaped,
但我非要大家回去找蜘蛛
but I made us go back for spider.
我们本就该回去
Then we have to go back.
那不是你的错
That's hot your fault.
把这话留给爸爸
Have that to dad.
我们本不该出现在那里
We werent even supposed to be out there.
我被逮住
I got this caught.
是因为我违抗了命令
Because I disobeyed orders.
那正是你啊  老弟
Thta's just you, little bro.
我爱你 哥
I love you bro.
你小子怎么回事
This is going on.
我害死了我哥
I killed my brother.
不管发生过什么 我的余生都要背负着它度过
No matter what happens, I have to live with that for the rest of my life.
我真希望我能做到
I wish I could do it.
我何尝不希望这样...
I wish I could do it...
...要是我没有在水下遭遇愚蠢的癫痫发作就好了
...if I've not of stupid seizure underwater.
是啊 谁叫你没戴面罩
Yep, you'd be me without a mask.
那咱就做个测试 看看会发生什么
Let's test that see waht happens.
怎么缝线的？怎么缝线的？
What's the stitches? What's the stitches?
像这样吗？哈？
Like that huh?
仇恨之火只留下悲伤之灰
The fire of hate leaves only the ash of grief.
我母亲以古老的方式哀悼
My mother mourned the ancient way.
在日食期间目睹儿子的生活
Seeing her son's life during the daily eclipse.
因为光明终归会重现......
Because the light always returns...
这不是我的哀悼方式...
There's the not me way...
...还有我爸爸的哀悼方式是 保持沉默 埋头做事
...and then there's my dad's way, say nothing, keeing busy.
岛礁族人说 大海能把你净化
The Reef People say the sea washes you clean.
洗去你的罪孽
Washes away your sins.
你找到了什么？
What do you got?
我们是来收集枪支的
We're supposed to be collecting guns.
我觉得这东西没用
Yours I think useless.
认真点 小子
Focus, boy.
别让你母亲看到
Don't let your mother see that.
借过
Excuse me.
嘿 借过 哈哈 图克
Hey, excuse me, ha ha Tuk.
快一点
Hurry!
兄弟
Bro.
我看到它了
I see it.
这是什么？
What's this?
提蕾娅
Tsireya.
你在干什么？
What are you doing?
这是一支AR突击步枪
This is an Armalite Rifle.
这个就是弹匣
This's the magazine.
还没上子弹
The bullets are empty.
拍它一下
Slap it.
瞄准目标
Bracket.
听到“砰”的一声
And then boom,
它会自动扫射
it can just spray.
你能用这个杀死大批骷髅
You can kill a lot of skeletons with this.
可参照陶瓷制作
See ceramic action.
只要把它们清洗干净并上油 就能恢复如新
Clean them and oil them be as good as new.
这不是我们纳美人的一贯作风 杰克·萨利
This is not the Na'vi way,  Jake Sully.
我们禁止使用金属武器
Weapons of mtal are forbidden.
你很清楚 这东西一旦触碰会毒害人心
You know this to touch poisons the heart.
伊娃会眷顾我们
Eywa will provide.
哀悼期还没有结束
The mourning period is not even over.
图克 你应该和家人在一起
Tuk, you should be with your family,
而不是收集这些东西
not gathering these things
你的女人需要你
Your woman needs you.
我儿子和祖先们一同躺在礁石里
My son lies with the ancestors in the reef.
这是你的家乡
It's your home.
我说过我会站起来战斗
I said I would stand and fight.
但我不能使用长矛对抗武装直升机
But I can't fight gunships with spears.
我们击沉了恶魔船
We sank the demon.
如今 兽皮害怕我们了
The thingskins fear us now.
的确 上次我们很走运 而他们获得了更多的筹码
Yeah, we got lucky, and they got many more chips.
我们换来了这些
Which we got these.
我们很感激你与我们并肩作战 杰克·萨利
We are grateful you stand with us, Jake Sully.
我们需要的不是枪械
It is not guns we need.
而是驾驭“天空霸主”托鲁克的“魅影骑士”
It is rider of last shadow to ride the great Toruk.
就像你当年那样
As you did before.
当你驾驭野兽 你便成了野兽
When you ride the beast you become the beast.
而杀戮越多 罪孽越深
And the more blood the better.
我不会再当“魅影骑士”了
I will not become Toruk Makto again.
杰克·萨利
Jake Sully.
你永远是“魅影骑士”
You are always Toruk Makto.
来 奥农
Come, Aonung.
能听得见吗？
Can you hear me?
是的 我们能够清晰听到 请讲
Yeah, we can hear you loud and clear, go ahead.
我们已经把残骸里里外外都搜了个遍
So we've been through the wreck inside out.
还有我们在它方圆400米的区域进行了搜寻
And we searched through about 200-meter radius around it.
除了我们的同伙 并没有发现任何纳美人尸体
We didn't find any Na'vi' body just crew.
好吧......真不幸
Well...unluckily.
那请继续找 博士
Well, keep looking, doctor.
扩大搜寻范围
Expand the search radius.
明白了
I get it.
不过 士兵们发现了一种新型藻类
But soldiers discovered a nwe type of algae.
喂
Hello.
所以 他已经逃离了那里
So, he's got out of there.
还有另一种情况 也许有食腐动物把尸体拖走了
We don't know that scavengers could have carried off the bodies.
不 他逃走了
No, he made it out.
而他就躲在这个区域
And he's in this area.
那里只有寥寥几个村庄 只需给我一艘船
Down to a handful of villages you just give me a ship.
我已给过你一艘船
I gave you a ship.
它现在就躺在此处海底下
It's right there on the bottom.
还有我的团队
Along with my crew.
全军覆没
All dead.
你带我到那个鬼地方
You brought me out there.
为了一趟任务 足足飞行了26万亿英里
Twenty six trillion miles for a single mission.
跟一个家伙展开殊死搏斗
A kinetic hard-kill up against one guy.
但我毫无退缩
I ain't backing off.
喂 有人在吗
Everyone is here, hello.
欢迎回来
Welcome back！
这张弓承载着我祖先的精神
The spirit of my ancestors is in this bow.
我们的力量是什么？
What was our strength?
我能帮你修好它 洛阿克
I can help you fix it, Lo'ak.
不
No.
它已经给毁了
It's ruined.
我碰过的所有东西都给毁了
Everything I touch gets ruined.
他们从未谈及此事
They never talked about it.
但它就像一个斗牛士 静静地蹲伏在房间里
But it was there in the room like a crouching tenador.
我知道你永远不会放弃这张弓
I know you will never give up this bow.
所以......
So...
当它击中目标时 我们别靠太近
We're not too close when it hits.
所以你赞同罗娜尔的观点吗
So you agree with Ronal?
我绝不会在那女人面前说我丈夫的不是
I will never speak against my husband in front of that woman.
瞧瞧我在做什么
Look at what I'm doing.
我不能拿刀去拼命
Not taking a knife to a gunfight.
或接受赠予
Or to be given.
那我该做点什么？
So what am I supposed to do.
我跑也不行 打也不行
I can't run, and I can't fight well.
没错 伊娃会给予我们帮助 嗯
That's right, Ewya will provide...eh.
所以伊娃在哪里？她又在哪里？当我们的儿子......
So where was Eywa? Where was Eywa? When our son...
杰克......
Jake...
我在这地方已一无所有
I'm in this place where I have nothing.
与我无关的族人 与我无关的森林
Not my people, not my forest.
甚至连我父亲的弓也丢了
Even my father's bow is gone.
我唯一拥有的
All I have.
就是坚信这是”万灵之母“的旨意
It's my faith that this is the great mother's plan.
你还有这个家庭
You have this familly.
而且你还有我
And you have me.
我非常的爱你
And I love you so much.
总有一天你会让成为真正男子汉
There's one day gonna make you the man.
走 走
Go, go.
这实在太疯狂了
It's just too carazy!
哇呜......
Wow...
呜......
Ooooo...
啊哈......
Aha...
-噢 -爽
-Oh. -Yeah.
走走走走
Go, go, go, go.
呜哇！
Wow!
这真是爽到底了 你还好吗
That‘s insane, you good?
没毛病 兄弟
You're all right, bro.
我以为你要凉了
I thought you were dead.
哈哈......
Haha...
真糟糕 图鲲仍然被驱逐
It sucks that Tulkun still outcasts.
是啊
Yeah.
明明它救了我们所有人
After saving all our asses.
也不是
No.
我不是针对你 但换个角度想 图鲲也经受住了这种考验
I'm sorry, but by the token way he bears the tests.
包括所有在战斗中丧生的人
All those who died in the battle.
他们也经受了这些考验
They bears those tests.
我很抱歉 本是你拯救了大家的命
I'm sorry you should save us all.
没关系 我们是兄弟
No matter, we're brother.
你是我永远的兄弟
You're my forever brother.
我输了
I lose.
爹
Dad.
蜘蛛
Spider.
-等等 备用面罩在哪啊？ -我去找找
-Wait, where's the spare mask? -I'll go and find.
醒醒
Get up!
快啊 嘿 备用面罩呢？
Hurry up, hey. Where's the spare mask?
我找不到它
快啊 嘿 备用面罩呢？
Hurry up, hey. Where's the spare mask?
备用面罩到底在哪啊？
Where's the spare mask?
-你之前有在用 放哪了？-我不知道
-You used to be there, where is it? -I don't know.
快找
Find it!
不在这儿
It's not here.
告诉我它在哪？
Speak to me where is it?
我找不到它
I can't find it.
蜘蛛 嘿 面罩在哪里？
Spider, hey, where is it？
加油！加油！
Come on. Come on.
我找到了 爹
I got it, dad.
爹
Dad.
赶快
Hurry.
深呼吸
Breathe.
慢慢来 深呼吸
Breathe deep and slow.
深吸 慢点
Deep and slow.
蜘蛛 你见好点吗？
Spider, you okay？
好点了
Okay.
我没事了
没事了
Okay.
无赖
Scoundrel.
你必须要小心点
You must be careful.
小心谨慎是我的代名词
Careful is my middle name.
无赖 你以后要小心加倍
Shoundrel, you should be more careful.
认真点听话
Pays attention.
逃罚 逃罚 逃罚
Get off, get off, get off.
以后要小心谨慎加小心 认真听话......
More and more careful, pay ateention...
为什么吹角？
Why blow the bugle?
是”风之商人“
The wind traders.
”风之商人“到了
The wind traders are here.
”风之商人“来了
The wind traders are coming.
快点
Come on.
图克 我们走
Tuk, let's go.
快来啊
Come on.
嘿
Hey.
瞧瞧
Look.
瞧他
Look at him.
他占不了太多空间
He's not gonna take up much room.
只要他不惹麻烦就行
As long as he's no trouble.
放轻松 咱们走吧
Take it easy, let's go.
图克 琪莉
Tuk, Kiry.
琪莉 快点好嘛
Kiri, please.
今天是糟糕的一天
Today is bad day.
你们母亲和我已经决定好了
Your mother and I have come to a decision.
蜘蛛 你明天要回到高营地
Spider you're back in high camp tomorrow.
什么？
What?
“风之商人”会带你回去
The wind traders would talke you
不 爹
No, dad.
他不能走
He can't.
听着 蜘蛛
Listen, spider.
呆在这你只能依靠面罩来生活
You can live in a mask day and night.
我只想和你们待一起
I just want to stay here with you.
我知道
I know.
但这太冒险了
But it's just too risky.
这不公平
This isn't fair.
求你了 我很清楚 你们才是我唯一的家人
Please, you're the only family, I've ever know.
这是对你最好的选择
This is what's best for you.
但是 爹
But dad,
他是我们最好的朋友
he's our best friend.
难道找不到办法了吗？
Can't we just find a way?
太危险了
It's too dangerous.
那节电池一旦没电 你也会没命
The one dead battery away from being dead yourself.
他本该回到自己的种族身边
He belongs with his own kind.
娘
Mom.
哪个种族呢？母亲
And what kind is that, mother?
“天空人”？
Alien?
粉肤族人？
Pink skins?
-琪莉..... -够了
-Kiri... -Stop.
你太讨厌他们了 你眼里只有仇恨 他可是蜘蛛啊
You hate them so much, that's all you see. It's spider.
拜托 杰克萨利先生
Please, Jake. Mr.Sully.
你知道 我不会有任何麻烦的
I won't be any problem you know that.
爹 这并不合适
Dad, this isn't right.
蜘蛛也是这个家庭的一分子
Spider is part of this family.
他永远不会成为这个家庭的一分子
He will never be a part of this family.
由商队来运送他是最好不过了
The caravan is the safest way to move him.
不 拜托
No, please.
-他今天就起程 -拜托你不要这样做
-He's going today. -You can't do that, please.
就这么定了
You must do this.
-不 -够了
-No. -Stop.
这是一家庭
This is a family.
而不是搞民主 懂吗？
It's not a democracy, all right?
我恨你
I hate you.
你这是怎么了？
This is why?
我最好的宝贝女儿
My best baby girl.
不 不
No...no.
-没事的  -别碰我
-It's okay. -Don't touch me.
没事的
It's okay.
-你明白吗？-不
-You understand? -No.
我已经失去了哥哥
I allready lost my beother.
我不想再失去任何人了
I can't lose anyone else.
所以我们要团结一致
So we should stick together.
是的 这是家族的座右铭
Yep, that's the family motto.
-简直扯淡  -这不公平
-It's bullshit. -This isn't fair.
好吧
Okay.
嘿 还好吗？这样怎么样？
Hey, all right? How about this?
我们一起送他回去
We all got together to drop him off.
琪莉
Kiri.
你说你想去看望你祖母
You said you wanted to see your grandmother.
对 正好我们全家人来一次冒险之旅
Yeah, it will be an adventure for the whole family.
是的 也好
Yeah, too.
嘿 待在这儿
Hey, stay here.
我们的约定里只是粉肤男孩一人
Our arrangement was for the pink skin boy only.
我们不会有任何麻烦的
It won't be any trouble.
你本就是个麻烦
You are already trouble.
交易者必须自由行动
The trader must move freely.
我们不能选择立场
We cannot choose sides.
让“魅影骑士”加入商队...
Having Toruk Makto on board...
...无异于以这种方式选边站
...cuts very close to choosing a side in this war.
也许你搞错了 “魅影骑士”从未登上过你的船
Maybe you're mistaken. Toruk Makto was never on your ship.
但如果他有登船
But if he was ever aboard.
这样的话 他的女人会很乐意驾驭他的卫护队陪同飞行
Then he with his woman would be happy to fly his outriders.
保护商队
and protect caravan.
但愿如此
I hope so.
如今 灰烬族(芒克万族)的掠夺者变得愈发好斗了
The Mangkwan raiders grow more aggressive now.
那好吧 我接受你的提议
Very well, I meet you on this.
启动船只
Start the boat.
快来
Come on.
启动船只
Start the boat.
启动船只航行
Start the boat journey.
洛阿克
Lo'ak
提蕾娅......
Tsireya...
洛阿克 啊哈 嘿嘿嘿
Lo'ak, aha, hey, hey, hey.
掉转船头
Turn the boat!
掉转船头 所有人员就位
Turn the boat, all in positions.
请停下
Stop please.
迎风一跃而下
Windward made a jump fall.
举起来  逆风扬帆
Hold up and raise follow to windward.
提升 提升 提升
Lift...lift...lift
闪电船平缓驶来了
Linghtning Ship comes up easy.
迎风 我们走
Windward, let's go.
每个人都以自己方式表示哀悼
Everyone mourns in their own way.
对我来说 就是独自待在这里
For me, it's being up here alone.
我感觉到他与我同在
I feel him with me.
兄弟 快看这个
Bro, check it out.
我在风中听到他的声音
I hear his voice in the wind.
拿着这个
Hold this.
爹 我一直在想
Dad, I've been thinking.
嗯？
Eh?
我应该带上步枪 跟你一起战斗
I should carry a rifle and I can fight with you.
嗯
Eh.
那是早晚的事
That's gonna happen.
那你为什么不教我射击？
Why not you trained me to shoot?
好吧 我清楚自己在做什么
Okay, I know what I'm doing.
通信器呢？我已经跟你说好几遍了
Where's comms? I told you five times.
你的通讯器在哪里？
Where're your comps?
这是第一规则
rule number one.
你连这个都做不到
You can't even do that.
就是这里
That's it.
你能找到它吗？
Would you get it?
当然 我敢打赌 这家伙是有备而来的
Sure. I promise this guy will imagine in case of bears...
...if he gets force.
远程控制系统已锁定他们的一举一动
Long-range controls to these guys when they punch.
我们的空域例行飞行系统也已经升级
Our airspace routine flybys enhanced.
微笑吧 婊子
Smile bitches.
-什么时候行动？ -今天下午一点五十分
-When? -13:50 today.
我们掌握了定位坐标
We have coordinates.
现在 让我们鼓起士气
Let's man up now.
谢谢你
Thank you.
保持镇定
Hold it heart.
Holy heart.
灰烬部落的首领 瓦琅
The sheilk fo the Mangkwan, Varang.
带领灰烬族人在火山地带发动伏击
Led the Ash People to launch an ambush in the volcanic area.
你的电池？
Your pack?
我很好 我还有充足的时间
I'm good, I got plenty time.
终于畅通无阻了
Clear the hinder.
杰克 是灰烬族
Jake, the Mangkwan!
船长 叫他们加速前进
Captain, have them speed up.
加快速度
Hurry up!
咱们动手吧
Let's do it.
图克 快走
Tuk, go.
快走
Go.
把他弄下来
Get him down.
来吧 我们走 图克 快
Come on, let's go. Tuk, go.
伊娃主佑
Eywa.
快走 快走
Go, go.
-保护好你妹妹 听到了吗？-收到 长官
-You protect your sister, do you hear?. -Yes, sir.
快藏起来
Stay in cover.
蜘蛛 留着吧
Spider, keep it！
该死 我的通讯器
Shit, my comms.
和女孩待在一块 去吧
You stay with girls, go.
你要去哪里？
Wher are you going?
不 你应该留在这里
No, you should stay here.
快来
Come on.
回来
Get back.
我即烈焰
I'm the fire.
走 走 走
Go, go, go.
朋友 朋友
Frie, frie.
我们快上去
Let's go up quickly.
蜘蛛 驾龙离开
Spider, drive off.
来吧 我们走
Come on, let's go.
咕噜......
Gulu...
奈蒂莉 奈蒂莉 你收到了吗？
Neytiri, Neytiri, do you copy?
该死......
Shit...
伙计们 慢一点
Guys, slow off!
我们必须跟上 快 快
We've got to keep up, go, go.
洛阿克？
Lo'ak?
跳
Jump.
快 来吧 跳！
Go, come on. Jump!
走走走走走
Go, go, go, go, go.
哦 上帝
Oh, god.
大家挺住
Hold on, everyone,
Hold on, hold on.
挺住 挺住
抓稳 图克
Hold on tight, Tuk.
蜘蛛
Spider.
琪莉
Kiri.
我的腿
My legs.
拔
Pull.
你没事吧？
You okay?
Tuk.
图克
图克 图克
Tuk, Tuk.
嘿 你没事吧？
Hey, are you okay?
兄弟 你还好吧？
Bro, you good?
还好
Yeah.
对不起 可爱的姑娘 可爱的姑娘
I'm sorry. Sweet girl, sweet gril.
真对不起 没事的......
I'm so sorry. It's okay...
好了
Just it.
不 放开她
No, let her go.
谢谢你
Thank you.
哥们 飞船在哪里？
Bro, where's the spaceship.
什么？
What?
我的备用物品放在那艘船上
My backups stored on that ship.
该死
Shit.
琪莉 待在这儿
Kiri, Stay it.
看
Look.
在那里 抓住他们
There, get them.
快撤 快撤
Hurry go! Hurry go!
该死
Shit!
来吧 快点走
Come on, hurry go.
琪莉 快跑！琪莉 快跑！来吧
Kiri, run! kiri, run! come on.
快 快
Go, go.
他们来了 快跑 我们走
They're coming, Run! let's go.
继续走 走走走走走
Keep going. GO, go, go, go, go.
琪莉 跑
Kiri, run.
这边
This way.
加油 图克
Come on, Tuk.
跟着我！
Follow me!
洛阿克 洛阿克
Lo'ak, Lo'ak!
妈的怎么回事？
What the fuck?
酋长 你看！
Sheikh, look!
刀！
Knife!
跟我来
Follow me.
加油
Come on.
图克 手给我
Tuk, give me your hand.
在那里 快追
There, chase!
图克 他们追来了
They're coming, Tuk.
3,4 往这边
Three four, this way.
快走 快走
Go, go.
加油
Come on.
别停下
Keep going.
加油
Come on.
这边 快点
This way, come on.
Keep runing, keep runing, go , go, go.
继续跑 继续跑 快快快
加油 加油
Come on, come on.
洛阿克！
Lo‘ak!
去他妈的游泳
Fuck the swimming!
别跑
Don't run.
我终于明白了 图克
I got it, Tuk.
父亲常提那句话是什么意思了
To dad, what's that
所以我们要团结一致
So we stick together.
不 滚开
No, get away.
-所以我们永不放弃？-说得对
-So we never quits? -That's right.
所以我们永不放弃
So we never quits.
什么也看不到
Nothing to see.
琪莉！
Kiri!
蜘蛛.....
Spider...
图克 抓住我的手
Tuk, Hold my hand.
噢 上帝
Oh, god.
琪莉？琪莉？
Kiri?...Kiri?
蜘蛛......蜘蛛？
Spider?...Spider?
抓住......抓住我的手
Got...got my hand.
噢 上帝
Oh, god.
重复 收到请回答？
Echo, do you copy?
洛阿克 快接 小子 回答我
Lo'ak, come in, boy, answer me.
你有听到我说话吗？
Did you have copy?
图克蒂蕾 图克蒂蕾 能收到吗？
Tukirey, Tukirey, do you copy?
奈蒂莉 奈蒂莉 收到请回答？
Neytiri, Neytiri, do you copy?
图克！
Tuk!
快点游
Quick swim.
走
Go.
我们要去哪里？
Where are we going?
加油
Come on.
我拉住你的手
I get to your hands.
大家都没事吧？
Is everybody okay?
你还好吗？
You okay?
-蜘蛛 你能走吗？-嗯 我还行
-Spider. you can go? -Yeah, I'm good.
你们有看到他们吗？
Did you see them?
没有
No.
我们到外面去吧
Let's get outside.
我想回家
I wanna go home.
图克 来吧
Tuk, come on.
我现在又累又饿 我想回家
I'm tired and I'm hungry. I wanna go home.
爹无法知道我们在哪
Dad has no idea where're we.
我们没有通讯器
We get no comms.
现在我们唯有靠自己了
We're on our own.
兄弟 我得换一副面罩了
Bro, I've got to exchange a mask.
那我们该怎么办？
What are we gonna do?
我不知道 为什么我来负责？
I don't know. Why am I in charge?
冷静点
Calm down.
我们必须做点什么
We have to do something.
别响
Shut up.
洛阿克？
Lo'ak?
走吧走吧走吧
Go, go, go.
我们得回到船上
We have to go back to the ship.
不 我们不能回去
No, we can't go back to the ship.
那些家伙就在半途等着呢
Those guys are between us and the ship.
我们已经知道他们的具体位置
That's our last known position.
到那时 老爹也会在那里找到我们
That's where dad's gonna be looking for us.
兄弟 不行
Bro, no.
我们只要绕开他们就行
We just circle around them?
好主意
It's good idea.
往哪里走？
Which way?
往主边走 来吧 跟着我
This way. Come on, follow me.
你要完蛋了 杰克
It's all over, Jake.
站住 别乱动
Stay real still.
这就是你要找的人吗？
Is that who you got?
好啦
All right.
够了
Enough!
那么 自作聪明的儿子
So smartass son.
把手伸出来
Extend your hands.
手！
Hands!
我.....我明明杀了你
I...I killed you.
也许是我命不该绝吧 下士
I guess I don't die that easy corporal.
帮帮.....帮帮我
Help...help me.
是谁把你伤成这样 下士
Who hit you, corporal?
我的战友
My comrades.
他们管那些人叫“灰烬人”
They call those the Ash People.
这是什么个情况？
What's this?
他们砍杀船员 并夺取敌人的脚趾来示威
They cut the crew and take their enemy's toes at the power.
对于那些人来说 这比死更可怕
That's worse than death to these guys.
你看见他了吗？
Did you sight him?
孩子们都跑了
Kids are gone.
电量还是满的
That's fully charged.
也就是说他没来得及换面罩就跑掉了
Which means he missed his mask change and he ran out.
而这就是那些“灰烬人”没能先逮住他的原因
And that's these Ash People don't get to him first.
我们现在赶紧去寻找这些孩子
We hurry to go after these kids right now,
不然你以后再也见不到他了
or you're never gonna see him then.
你在追踪他们吗？
Do you track them?
这可不在我们的任务范畴内
That is not the mission what are we doing?
你能追踪到他吗？
Can you track him?
我们在浪费时间 上校
We're burning time colone, colonel.
头儿 我们费了九牛二虎之力才抓到他
Boss, we got him very hard.
不 手铐还是要戴
No, the cuffs stay there.
往哪边走？
Which way?
我怕你会再次被杀
I fear you'll get killed again.
来吧 往这边走
Come on, this way.
河流应该就在前面不远处 快点
The river's got to be just up ahead. Come on.
蜘蛛
Spiser!
兄弟
Bro!
它没电了
It's stuck.
我们该怎么办？
What should we do?
我的幸运男孩 你会逢凶化吉的
My lucky boy, you will turn your luck.
看着我 慢点呼吸
Look at me, take slow breaths.
洛阿克 你能背他走吗？
Lo'ak, can you carry him?
上来 兄弟 我来背你
Come on, bro. I'll carry you.
来吧
Come on.
孩子们跑到水里去了
Kids ran at the water.
明智之举
Smart move.
哦 天啊 不......
Oh, god. No...
蜘蛛......
Spider...
“万灵之母”我恳求您 快来救救您的天空人吧
Great mother save your Sky People first, I beg you.
没时间去恳求了 他快要死了
It's no time to beg and he's dying.
拜托
Please!
你会没事的 兄弟
You'll be okay, bro.
深呼吸
Just breathe.
琪莉 琪莉 我们要走了 快啊
Kiri, Kiri, we need to go, come on.
琪莉 你确定要坐在那里吗 我们得动身了
Kiri, did you sure sit around there, we have to go.
琪莉 你确定要坐在那里吗 我们得继续前进了
Kiri, did you sure sit around there? We got to keep going almost there.
你确定要坐在那里吗 我们得走了
Did you sure sit around there? We got to go.
她就在那里
Just over there.
琪莉 来吧
Kiri, come on.
停下
Stop.
快带他过来
Bring him here.
停下
Stop.
快点
Quickly.
停下
Stop.
照我说的做
Do as I say.
把他放在这里
Put him here.
停下 琪莉 你在干什么？
Stop, Kiri, what are you doing?
你在干什么？
What are you doing?
你这是要干嘛？
我知道这种方法 但我从未试过
I'm know this way, but this way I never tried.
什么？
What?
安静点 我不能说话
Be quiet, I can't talk.
洛阿克 洛阿克
Lo'ak, Lo'ak!
这副面罩 把它摘下
This mask take it off.
什么？
What?
他无法呼吸
He can't breathe.
快点
Come on.
琪莉......
Kiri...
别啊 洛阿克
No, Lo'ak.
别
No.
哦 不
Oh, no.
蜘蛛！
Spider!
我能呼吸了
I'm breathing.
是的 幸运儿
Yes, lucky boy.
你就是
You are.
我死了？
I'm dead?
这里是灵魂世界
This is the spirit world.
不 伙计 你还活着
No, guys. You're still here.
我能正常呼吸啦
I‘m breathing the air.
是啊
Yeah.
我能正常呼吸啦
I'm breathing the air.
我也能正常呼吸啦......
I'm breathing the air...
我以后再也用不着戴这该死的破面罩了
I guess I don't need this mask shit anymore.
是啊 我们都在这 太好了
Yeah, we're here, baby!
耶
Yeah.
别 别 安静......快停下
No, no, quiet...stop it!
谢谢你
Thank you.
蜘蛛
Spider.
感谢你为我所做的一切
Whatever you did, thank you.
噢 该死 后退！
Oh, shit! Give back!
寻找掩护 寻找掩护
Seek cover! Seek cover!
小心
Watch out!
走
Go.
蜘蛛！
Spider!
不
No.
酋长 这里
Sheikh, here!
他没戴面罩怎么可能呼吸呢？
How is he breathing with no mask?
我没功夫去纠结这问题
I can't thing about that.
现在我们救人要紧
Right now we gotta get in there.
我们的空气对天空人来说 不是毒药吗？
Is not our air poison to Sky People?
你每天到底怎么活下来的？
How do you still live every day?
因为这是伊娃的旨意
Because it's the will of Eywa.
伊娃？
Eywa?
没错
Yes.
如果我现在割了他
If I cut him now,
你觉得伊娃会不会来救他？
do you think Eywa will come to save him?
来吧 帮我把手铐解开
Come on, get cuffs off me.
快啊 他要对他动手了
Come on, they'll kill him.
你觉得呢？
Do you think?
不
No.
这里我说了算 你的"圣母"也救不了你们
Your goddess has no dominion here.
来吧
Come on.
那把刀借我用用
Then give me the knife.
你！
You!
你来示范给我看看 这玩意咋操作
You show me how this works.
快示范我看看 怎么使它打雷
Show me how to make it thunder.
好吧 它没子弹 没法打雷
Okay, it's empty, no thunder.
快使它打雷！
Make it thunder!
我说了 它没子弹
Okay, it's empty.
快点搞！
Make it quick!
我跟你说了 我已经跟你说了 它没法打雷
I told you, I told you, it's no thunder.
把最小那个宰了
Kill the youngest one.
别别别别别 求你求你 放过他
No, no, no, no, no. Please, please, no.
放下武器！
Weapons down!
放下！
全部放下！
Lay all down!
现在退后
Now keep back.
退后
Back.
继续
Go on.
退远点！
Step back!
退后 退后
Keep back! Keep back!
爹
Dad.
萨利 好了吗？
Sully, good?
好了
Ready.
孩子们 跟我走
Kids, follow me!
那好吧 现在我们慢慢离开这里
All right. We gonna slowly leave here.
跟紧我！跟紧我！
Follow me! Follow me!
不 爹
No! Dad!
不 爹！
No, dad!
爹......
Dad...
你是条硬汉
You are strong.
天空人
Sky man.
你......示范我看看 怎样使它打雷
You...show me how to make it thunder.
还要配上这个
And that's the match.
我来教你
Show you.
现在就瞄准你想打的目标
Now you take aim what do you want to hit.
然后像我这样扣动板机
Then just go like this.
对
Yeah.
继续
Go on!
干得漂亮
It's good done.
哇
Wow.
你现在对我没用了 天空人
I do not need you now, Sky man.
把他绑好
Bind him well.
跪下
On our knees.
准备献祭仪式
Prepare for sacrifice.
奈蒂莉
Neytiri!
按住她
Hold her down.
奈蒂莉
Neytiri.
我们已帮你拔出箭了 你会好起来的
We got you, you'll be okay.
你会没事的 我们就在你身边
You'll be okay, we got you.
麦克斯 准备手术
Max, prep for surgery！
快 把门尽量敞开
Go, open more doors.
这些家伙把结系得真够牢
These guys know theirt knots.
伙计们 快点
Guys, come on.
加油
Come on.
走 别停下
Go, move it.
是那个小女孩干的 来吧
It was the girl.
快啊 大家往这边来
Come on, get in this way.
走吧
Let's go.
加油
Come on.
快走
Go.
琪莉 快走
Kiri, go.
酋长！
Sheikh!
他们不见了
They are gone.
我们空中搜索
We search by air.
敬爱的伊娃 请帮助我们
We need you, beloved Ewya.
别动 孩子
敬爱的伊娃 请帮助我们
We need you, beloved Ewya.
谢天谢地
Thank goodness.
放松点 放松点
Easing, easing.
麦克斯！
Max!
别动 孩子
Keep still, child.
别 别
No, no.
不要
No.
冷静点
Calm down.
我的孩子们
My children.
奈蒂莉！
Neytiri!
我的孩子们
My children.
闺女 你冷静点
Daughter, keep calm.
我的孩子们 我的孩子们......
My children, my children...
在哪儿？
Where?
他们在哪里？
Where are they?
来吧 手脚麻利点 麦克斯 让我进去
Come on, let's hustle. Max. Get me in.
好的 好的
Yeah, yeah.
我们热吗？
Are we hot?
非常热
Very hot.
好吧 最好别穿衣服
All right, don't ever wear clothes.
你必须听话 孩子
You must listen, my child.
闺女
Daughter.
再见
Goodbye.
谢谢你
Thank you.
我会找到的
I will find.
回来......哦 不
Come... oh, no.
好了
Okay.
我来帮你
Let's help you.
这地方挺适合休息
This is good place.
我们安全了
We're clear.
是的
Yeah.
正好我们该来算算我们之间的账了
Which brings us to our unresolved issues.
可我的箭已经丢了
But my arrows has lost.
我们的刀还在
Still got our knives.
他们实在太困了
They're all kind of tired.
确实
Yeah.
对啊 我们最好养精蓄锐
Yeah, better save it.
我相信那些飞猴不一会就来了
I trust those flying monkeys will come soon.
那是当然
Yeah, sure.
我相信现在去做还为时未晚
You wouldn't miss much then so late I'll belive that.
他是个好孩子
He's a good kid.
他确实是个很不错的孩子
He's a great kid.
嘿 但即便是这样 我们也不会成为朋友
Hey,but...this doesn't mean we're taking long walks together.
如果有必要 我还是会把你抓起来的
I'm still bringing you in hand if I have to.
到现在你还是执迷不悟
All this time out here you still don't get it.
这个世界远比你想象中的要深得多
This world goes much deeper than you imagine.
今晚你已经见识过了
You witnessed it tonight.
和她
With her.
还有他
And him.
不重要
Don't matter.
我是生是死并不重要
It don't matter what color I am.
我仍然记得自己在为哪个团队效力
I still remember what team I'm playing for.
你已经有了新的眼睛 上校
You've got new eyes, colonel.
你要做的就是打开它们
All you gotta do is open them.
是灰烬族
It's the Ash.
快起来
Get up.
来吧 我们得动身了
Come on, we gotta move.
快点 我们得动身了
快啊 我们赶紧走吧
Come on, come on. We hurry go.
没事了 没事了
It's okay, it's okay.
他们是我们的人 是自己人
They're ours, they're ours.
杰克
Jake.
谢天谢地！
Thank goodness!
琪莉 图克
Kiri, Tuk.
你们伤着没有？
Are you hurt?
你们是怎么找到我们的？
How did you find us?
孩子们！
Children!
奈蒂莉！
Neytiri!
妈妈
Mama
噢 图克
Oh, Tuk.
图克
Tuk.
琪莉
Kiri.
洛阿克
Lo'ak.
杰克
Jake.
你还好吗？
Are you okay?
嗯 没事了 我们相安无事了
Yeah, it's okay, we are okay.
伊诺
Eno.
怎么了？
What's up?
什么情况？
What?
老兄
Dude.
哦 是这样
Oh, yeah.
现在我能在整片空气中自由呼吸了
I'm good on the whole air today.
图克 过来这儿
Tuk, come here.
琪莉
Kiri.
太好了
So good.
我超喜欢铁天蓝色
Iron Sky Blue I enjoy.
我们正在前往城墙的路上
We're inbound at the city wall.
所以你觉得他现在还和萨利在一块吗？
So you think he still with Sully?
我敢拿奖金打赌
I'd bet bonus on it.
这可不是我的首要任务
This is not my priority,
我的首要任务是建好这座城市...
My priority is getting this city well built...
然后把“甘露”送回来抵偿这笔费用
...and sending back amrita to pay for it.
那么 你认为是谁决定了你的首要任务？
Then who do you think sets your priority?
这才是关键所在 伙计们
It's the big picture, guys.
下面我有个整体思路与你们分享
So here's a big picture concept for you.
我们该如何去殖民这个世界？
How are we supposed to colonize this world?
假如我们连该死的空气都不能呼吸？
If we can't breathe the freaking air?
你想找到那个小子 那就得找到萨利
You want to find that boy, you gotta find Sally.
然后 按压那里
And press there...
哦 天啊 像这样的还要做多少次
Oh, my god, how many more of these?
嗯 没几次了
Huh, not many more.
他们昨天也这么说
Since they said yesterday.
这是最新的扫描结果
Here's the most recent scan that.
你看到这些了吗？
And you see this?
这些都是菌丝体
This is all mycelium.
这跟木维网基本没什么区别
It's basically the same thing as the forest network.
不知何故 这些菌丝侵入了他的身体 并向其全身组织蔓延
Somehow it colonized him and spread through his entire system.
然后在细胞层面作出了改变
Then made changes at the cellular level.
我是说 你看
I mean, look,
这些菌丝不仅改变了他的血液化学成分
It altered his blood chemistry,
还有他的神经系统 他的肺......
his nervous system, his lungs...
你能把菌丝取出来吗？
Can you get it out?
不行 这是内共生体
No, it's an endosymbiont.
我们认为他们是相互依存的
We think they're keeping each other alive.
一旦我们尝试取出 他就会没命
They could kill him if we even try.
但你看 他活着的时候 身体很棒
But look, when he's alive, he's healthy.
这未尝不是好事
Maybe this is good things.
是好事
Good things.
你想想看 要是RDA实验室能进行反向工程会怎样？
What if the rda labs could reverse engineer?
再有 要是地球上的每个人...
What if every human being on earth...
...都能不戴面具在这里生活呢？
could live here without a mask?
这个嘛 杰克.....
Ah, Jake...
你还有其他想法吗？
Is there something else?
坐
Sit.
嘿 伙计
Hey, bud!
好的
Okay.
你别动 别动 没事的
Hold still, hold still, you're fine.
怎么样？
How?
看看哪里
Look at that.
那是什么？
What is that?
他头上长出了一个葫芦
It's grown a hulu.
等等
Wait.
什么？
What?
哦 是的
Oh, yeah.
万灵之母
Great mother.
您在吗？
Are you there?
请......倾听我细小的声音
Please...hear my small voice.
我曾在森林里向您祈祷拯救我的朋友
I prayed to you in the forest to save my friend.
我满怀虔诚祈祷您
I prayed so hard.
可你没有来
But you didn't come.
你没回应 所以我只好自己解决
You didn't answer, so I had to do it myself.
我不知道当时是怎么恳求的
I don't know how I asked?
I asked the roots to help me.
我恳求树根给予我帮助
I don't ever remember how.
我完全记不起来是怎么做到的
求你 别
Please, on.
别 别把我拒之门外
No, don't shut me out.
我那时为什么会这样做？
Why am I like this?
我又是怎么把这些事情做到的？
How am I doing these things?
请跟我说说话吧
Please just talk to me.
别 别 拜托 拜托了
No, no, please, please.
不要......
No...
琪莉 你是怎么做到的？
Kiri, how did you do it?
伊娃从来没有找过我
Eywa never came to me.
我告诉过你 我不知道我是怎么做到的
I told you I don't know how I did it.
喝点水吧 琪莉
Drink water, Kiri.
我的孩子 你曾被你生母的手轻抚过
My child, you were touched by the old mother's hand.
这事从你出生之日起我们就已经知道
This we have known since you were born.
你有事瞒着我
There is something you're hiding.
我一辈子都有这种感觉 就告诉我真相吧
I have felt it my whole life, just tell me the truth.
拜托你们了
Please.
告诉她吧
Tell her.
是时候了
It is time.
我的孩子
My child.
其实你并没有父亲 ......琪莉
You do not have a father...Kiri.
什么？
What?
你的......
Your...
你的亲生母亲是格蕾丝博士的化身
Your real mother by Dr.Grace's avatar.
And when she was pregnant, Norm ran some tests.
她怀孕的时候 诺姆曾做了一些测试
Result shows you was a prrt...parthenogenetic birth.
结果显示你是......你是单性生殖的产物
而且你与阿凡达的基因完全相同
And you're genetically identical to the Avatar.
也就是说你真的没有父亲
There literally is no father.
我是个克隆人？
I'm a clone?
听着孙女 此乃母神之旨意也
Granddaughter it was the will of Eywa.
当梦行者的躯体趟在万灵之母的怀抱时
When the dream walker's body lay here in the great mother's arms.
那时 已悄然播下一颗种子
A seed was planted.
真可怕
That really sucks.
让我感觉自己更像个怪物
That makes me even more of a freak.
不是的 孙女
No, greanddaughter.
你是神明的孩子
You are Eywa's child.
不管你是什么
I don't care how it happened.
你都是我宝贝女儿
You're my baby girl.
我是你唯一依靠的父亲
And I'm the only father you'll ever need.
要是我真的那么特别
If I am so special.
那为什么伊娃对我充耳不闻？
Why does Eywa fold her ears to me?
听着 我们也不知为什么
Look, we don't know why.
但你被她拒之门外
But you're locked out from her.
这是某种防火墙
It's some kind of firewall.
是啊 甚至设置了加密
Yeah, even set encrypted.
你试图强行入侵 它的防御反制就越强
The harder you try to break in, the harder it fights back.
伊娃给你指引了一条路
Eywa has a path for you though.
尽管她选择了隐瞒
Though she chooses to conceal it.
但你一定要相信她
You must trust in her.
我一定要寻根问底
I have to find out what it is.
不行 你必须停止追问
No, you have to stop asking.
琪莉 你要是要是要是尝试再次连接 你可能会没命
Kiri, if if if you try to connect again, you could die.
在水下干这事会危及你的生命
You do it underwater and you will die.
一旦ODA成功抓获他 他就不能待在这
He can't stay here if the ODA gets him.
我们俩从不阻拦他
We both never stop him.
要是他严重危及百姓以及万物
If he so dangerous to the people to everything.
那我们只好亲手灭了他
We are just kill him.
他可是蜘蛛啊
It's spider.
他会站在我们这边 和我们一同去岛礁
He'll come with us, he'll come to the reef.
到了那边 我们就能保护他
We can protect him there.
魅影骑士 别回头！
Toruk makto, don't look back!
拜托 亲爱的
Come on, baby.
不是这样的
It's not like that.
既然你决定了
It is decided.
第30小组 让他们嗨起来开始行动
30th team, get them up getting.
把我送进“驱乐捕”
Get me in the Club.
十分钟后 把我连同火箭一起送进“驱乐捕”
Get me in the Club with the rocket ten minutes.
继续前进！
Still go!
瞄准！
Aim!
侥幸得分！
Lucky shot!
她姨妈来了 呜呼哀哉
She's bleeding out.
新的恶魔船比以前的恶魔船体型更大了
A new demon ship has come bigger.
越来越多的图鲲惨遭杀害
More and more Tulkun have been killed.
我很抱歉 兄弟
I'm so sorry, brother.
杰克·萨利
Jake Sully.
这个图鲲族的叛徒正在煽动年轻的公鲲
The Tulkun of outcast it stirring up the young bulls.
我们的图鲲已召开会议对他进行裁决
Our Tulkuns have called for a council to decide about him.
你们必须休息一下
You must rest.
This must be removed, see me.
这处伤口必须要清理 来我这一趟
孩子们 孩子们跟我来
Kids, kids come with me.
停 我是认真的
Stop, I'm serious.
等我头发长得足够长时
When it grows long enough,
我要拥有属于自己的伊鲁(坐骑)
I'm gonna get my own Ilu.
想得美！
Get knotted!
你需要一头非常小的坐骑
You need a very small Ilu.
等着瞧吧 我会拥有专属的水上飞机
Just you watch, I'll get my own Skimmer.
到时我会去战斗
Then I'll be to fight.
那你的女儿最近还好吗？
So how is  your daughter?
你的混血女儿...
Your half blood daughter...
...没有受过训练
...with no training.
扛住
Holding up.
她却做了连酋长都做不到的事
Has done what no sheikh could do.
你有什么资格去质疑伊娃的旨意？
Who are you to question the will of Eywa?
-我是酋长  -那就当好你的酋长
-I'm a sheikh.  -Then be sheikh.
看来敷草药也是白搭
These herbs do nothing.
我在家乡的森林里愈合速度更快
I at my forest heal faster.
我叫你休息 你不休息
I tell you to rest, you do not rest,
反而怪我的草药不好
then you blame my herbs.
别乱动
Hold still.
你个无可救药的女人
Stupid woman.
酋长 说话放尊重点
Careful, sheikh.
否则我会忘记你肚里有孩子的事
Or I may forget that you are with child.
图鲲长老发话了
The matriarch has spoken.
她说 被驱逐者一再违抗规则
She says the outcast continues to defy.
图鲲族之道 禁止一切的杀戮行为
The Tulkun way all killing is forbidden.
他曾因此受到驱逐
He was outcast for this.
如今他重蹈覆辙
But he has done it again.
这个被驱逐者袭击了恶魔船
The outcast attacked the demon ship.
给我们的族人带来了灾难
Bringing death to our people.
“魅影骑士”之子也因此而死
Even the son of Toruk Mokto.
爹 他们不能把责任推卸给帕亚坎
Dad, they can't blame Payakan on that.
我知道
I know.
长老说 他一直在搞破坏
She says, he continues to disrupt.
企图把我们年轻一代引入歧途
Splitting bad ideas among our young.
一派胡言
It's bullshit.
他说谎
It's not true.
她还说 他在这只会害死更多的人
She says, he will only bring more death.
爹 你为什么不说句话？
Dad, why don't you say something?
拜托了 你就说几句吧
Just say something, please.
长老说 被驱逐者不许待在这片海域
She says, the outcast may not stay in these waters.
他必须远离这里...
He must go far...
...到一个没人知道的地方
...where his song cannot be heard exile for life.
终身流放
Exile for life.
这不公平
It's not fair.
那就这么定吧
You just decided.
我们永别了各位
Ihr werdet mein I ied nie wieder horen.
Ihr werdet mein Lied nie wieder horen.
别走
No.
帕亚坎
Payakan.
兄弟 求你 别走
Payakan, please, no.
帕亚坎......
Payakan...
这是......这是不对的 这是不对的
This is... this is wrong, this is wrong.
你别在这里闹事
You do not speak here.
不要
No.
帕亚坎曾经为我们而战
Payakan fought for us.
他曾帮过我们 对吗？
He fought for us, right?
洛阿克
Lo'ak.
还救了她一命
He saved her life.
你别在这里闹事
You do not speak here.
他被猎杀......
He defended...
这是会议通过的
This is council passed.
也是长老们的意思
The elders have spoken.
图鲲族正在被追捕
The Tulkun are being hunted.
他们在劫难逃
They have died.
洛阿克 够了
Lo'ak, that's enough.
不！
No!
洛阿克说的对
Lo'ak speaks the truth.
不！
No!
女儿！
Daughter!
帕亚坎是个英勇战士
Payakan is a warrior.
他比你们英勇多了
He fought for us more than you.
比你 比在座各位都英勇
More than you, more than any of you.
他为了我们而战
He fought for us.
Let him sit down.
叫他坐下
洛阿克 别说了
Lo'ak, no.
快给我拿下他 战士们
Take him, come on warriors.
琪莉 回家
Kiri, go home.
爹
Dad.
听他的话
Listen to hom.
会议还没开完呢
We are in council.
你必须跟我回家
You must go home with me.
放开我
Let me go.
你要干什么？
What are you doing?
你从来都不支持我
You never stand up for me.
保持冷静
Keep calm.
来吧 我们走
Come on, let's go.
我们继续开会
Council continues.
我们是在抗命
We're in war.
你明白吗？
You understand that?
要是你不服从命令 有人就会没命
If you disobey orders, people get killed.
听着 蜘蛛 我们客在他乡
Listen, spider here,
我们要尽量保持低调
we'll try to keep a low profile.
但那个混账就在外面
But that rogue is out there.
他在煽动年轻公鲲
He's stirring up the young bulls.
他要带领整个RDA来对付我们
He was gonna bring the whole RDA down on us.
你想要他走
You want him gone.
所以你才什么都不说
That's why you didn't say anything.
事实上 他跟你一样就是个冒失鬼
He's a loose cannon, he's just like you in fact.
要不是你当初去找他
If you hadn't gone to see him at that time.
要不是你违抗命令
If you hadn't disobeyed orders,
你哥他就不会......
and your brother still could be...
那不是我的错
That wasn't my fault.
我没有
I'm not.
那不是我的错！
That‘s not my fault!
洛阿克！
Lo'ak!
去看看吧 杰克
Go to see, Jake.
不然你会失去另一个儿子
Or you will lose another son.
我没什么可跟他说的
I've got nothing to say to him.
不要责怪洛阿克
Do not blame Lo'ak.
你说过你能保护这个家庭
You said you could protect this family.
你能做到的
That's you could do.
我想我们在这里会很安全
Yeah, I thought we woulld be safe here.
我们的儿子死了 杰克
Our son is dead, Jake.
是我错了吗？
I was wrong?
你想要我说什么？
What do you want me to say?
我为这个家所做的每个决定都是错的吗？
The every decision that I made for this family is wrong?
孩子是我杀死的吗？
I killed our son?
但事到如今 我们依旧在这个地方...
And still we are here in this place...
...藏匿着这个“粉肤人”
...hiding this pink skin.
这个外星人
This alien.
如果我必须在我的家人和“粉肤人”之间做选择的话
If I had to choose between my family and a pink skin.
我会马上宰了他
I would kill him right now.
停步 停步 停步
Stop, stop, stop.
你不能为么做 你不能这么做
You're not doing this, you're not doing this.
你已经在家人和“粉肤人”之间做过一次选择了
You already chose between your family and a pink skin ones.
记得吗？
Remember?
你不能像这个婴儿活在仇恨中
You cannot live like this baby in hate.
我恨他们 杰克
I hate them, Jake.
我恨他们
I hate them.
我恨他们那粉色的手
I hate their pink little hands.
我恨他们脑瓜里的疯狂
I hate insanity in their minds.
我是个人类
I'm a human.
在你心里
Inside.
你恨我吗？
You hate me?
我对你来说 永远是个异类
I'll always be an alien to you won't
无论多久我都在活在这副皮囊里
I doesn't matter how long I live in this skin.
那你恨孩子们吗？
You hate your children?
他们用着外星人的手
With their alien hands.
不恨
No.
你感到耻辱吗？
Are you ashamed?
每次他们都犯错 每次犯错都不同
Every time they make a mistake, every time they're different.
那是因为他们内心的人性 对吧？
That's because of the human inside them, right?
对不起......
I'm sorry...
眼下我们一定要坚强起来
We have to stand strong right now.
这个家是我们精神的堡垒 心灵的港湾
This family is our fortress and our harbour.
人们说当你开始接触钢铁时
The people say that when you touch steel,
毒药悄然渗入你的心
The poison seeps into your heart.
洛阿克！
Lo'ak!
兄弟
Brother.
洛阿克
Lo'ck.
不要轻生 要留住青山 老弟
Stay in this life, brother.
我们需要你
We need you.
我们爱你
We love you.
你身上拥有过人之处
You have greatness in you.
先人的力量凝聚于此
The strength of the ancestors is here.
弓坏了能修好
A bow can be fixed.
好 好
Good, good.
开始验货
A moment to link.
好的
Good!
哈哈
Haha.
Haha
去吧
Go.
你能与她相通吗？
You feel her?
哦 是的
Oh, yeah.
我有鳍了
I got fins.
是啊 你有鳍了
Yes, you do.
哇......
Whoa...
呜......
Oooo...
胆子肥点 去作死吧
Go, fucking way.
是他们叫我这样做的 他们叫的
They call like this, they call.
这个人 有人认识吗？
Stranger, does anyone know?
他们叫的
They call.
我觉得我们在浪费时间 上校
I think we're wasting our time, colonel.
他们什么都不知道
They can't know anything.
或者他们认识呢
Or they know.
只是不肯说而已
It's just that not talking.
我们还有一招 但有点极端
We got one more play but it's radical.
抓住他了！
Catched him!
你还记得我吗？我请你吃过饭呢
Do you remember me? I invited you to have dinner.
去你的
Screw you.
哇 哇 哇
Wow wow wow.
滚一边去！
Get out of here!
制住他
Hold him!
我想见你们酋长
I want to see meet your sheikh.
你把这个白痴带回去
You take this idiots out here.
嘿 嘿
Hey, hey.
没必要这样干 我认得你了
No need to do that, I got my eye on you.
酋长！
Sheikh!
瓦琅！
Varang!
我知道你野心很大 我能满足你想要的一切
I'll get you as many as you want.
你叫什么名字？天空人
What's your name? Sky man.
夸里奇
Quaritch.
迈尔斯·夸里奇 上校
Colonel Miles Quaritch.
你敢再用那支家伙碰我 我就灭了你们
You touch me with that thing again, I'll kill you.
你杀不了任何人
You will kill no one.
是吗？
Really?
听我命令 马上送他去领盒饭
I'm gonna beg the differ drop him.
哦 该死
Oh, heck.
勇气
Courage.
你会是下一个小甜点
You'll be next cupcake.
只是当心你现在意欲何为
Just be careful about what you want to do.
来
Come.
我们到里面谈谈
We will talk inside.
你这是要干什么？头儿
What will you do, boss?
哎呀 确实
By George,
问题是
the thing is,
所有人都不愿跟我说真话
everyone's lying to me.
我听说
They say that,
你能让石头道出真相
you can make stone speak the truth.
你在寻找另一个像你一样的天空人
You seek a man the other man like you.
他跟我不像
Not like me.
现在他成了叛徒
Now he's a traitor.
那他就得死
Then he must die.
但我会帮你找到这个人
But I'm gonna help you find this man.
还有你要寻找的这个人
And the other you seek.
现在他能呼吸空气了
He's can breather now.
首先 我得看看你的灵魂
First I must see your soul.
好吧
Yeah.
别动
Be still.
这劲头也太猛了 见鬼
That's so strong shit.
这就是......
This is...
这个世上最纯洁的东西
it's only pure thing in this world.
The fire came from the mountain when I was still little.
当我还很小的时候 一场突如其来的山火
烧毁了我们的森林
Burnt our forest.
夺走了我们的一切
It took everything.
我们的族人当时忍饥挨饿
My people were starving,
他们为此哭泣
they cried for it.
可是伊娃始终没来
But Eywa did not come.
于是我接近火焰
So I went to the fire.
并掌握了它的运作方式
And I learned it, its way.
我即烈焰 烈焰
I am the fire, fire.
依靠我的力量我的族人变得强大
By my hand my people grow strong.
我们不会坐而待毙
We do not lies dow and die.
就是因为这样 她选择了背叛我们
Just because it was turns her back on us.
我们也要选择背叛伊娃
We turn our back on Eywa.
软弱的母亲就配软弱的孩子
A weak mother for weak children.
我们不会吮吸软弱的胸脯
We do not suck in the breast of weakness.
哇
Wow.
唯有真话会从你口中说出来
Only true words will come from your tongue.
你拥有强大的心脏 无所畏惧
You have a strong heart, no fear.
这可不太好吧
That's wasn't cool.
我会吃掉你的心脏 夸里奇
I will eat your heart, Quaritch.
但你先回答我
But first you will answer me.
你来这里有何目的？
Why are you here?
我特意来找你的
I'm here for you.
你愿意效劳于我吗？
You wish to serve me.
我不效劳任何人
I don't serve anybody.
我需要你
I need you.
但我不需要你
But I do not need you.
但或许我会留着你 做我的奴隶来给我解闷
But I might keep you as my slave to pleasure me.
听起来挺不错 但是......
That sounds like a fun weekend. But...
这并非是你真正想要的
that's not what you really want.
那我真正想要的是什么？
Really what do I want?
你从未拥有过的东西
What you've never had.
同样平等
As equal.
你想把你的火焰蔓延至全世界
You want to spread your fire across the world.
我没说错吧？
Yeah?
我会给你枪械
I'll give you guns,
我会给你通讯器
I'll give you comms,
火箭弹
RPGs.
那可是威力强大的魔法
But that's strong magic.
有了它们 你就能决战千里 如雷霆般出击 所向无敌
Command from a distance strike like lightning.
The clans,
那些部落
你所飞及之处
as far as you can fly.
他们会在洞穴前鞠躬
They'll bow down before burrow.
你想与伊娃较量吗？
You wanna take on Eywa.
你需要我
You need me.
我懂你
I see you.
你说得对极了
Damn right you do.
等我可以再次连接的那天
When I can connect again someday.
无论何地 我都能带你前往灵魂世界
Wherever I can be your guide in the spiritual.
那我现在就可以去吗？
Well, can I just go now?
不 没有我可不行
No, not without me.
一个“天空族”的人不能突然冒出来吓唬祖先
A Sky Person can't just show up freak out the ancestours.
他们开始前来参加幼鲲圣餐仪式了
They're starting to arrive for the calf's communion.
满岁的幼鲲们还有那些新生婴儿都会聚到一块
Yearling calves and with babies together.
与伊娃建立第一次联系
Having their first bond with Eywa.
场面会很壮观
It'll be so beautiful.
让我看看
Let me see.
蛮好看
It's pretty.
我喜欢的菜
I like this one.
来参加节日吧
Come to the festival.
那我就在这陪你
Then I will just stay here with you.
洛阿克 我本不想告诉你这件事 不过......
Lo'ak, I should not tell you this, but...
我的图鲲姐妹说她们一直听到帕亚坎...
My Tulkun sister says they have been hearing Payakan...
...隐约呼唤他的族群
...very faint calling to his best friend.
在哪里？
Where?
图鲲的歌声能在水中传播非常远 洛阿克
Tulkun's song travels very far through the water, Lo'ak.
拜托了
Please.
唉
Ai.
洛阿克
Lo'ak.
再见了 娘
Buy, mum.
你要去哪里？
Where are you going?
留步
Stop.
有些事我得去做
There's something I have to do.
洛阿克！
Lo'ak!
洛阿克 等等
Lo'ak, wait.
别走 洛阿克
No, Lo'ak.
是的 我们必须找到帕亚坎 兄弟
Ja, wir mussen den Bruder von Payakan finden.
我们不能去
We cannot go.
幼鲲圣餐仪式在5天内举行
The calf's communion is in five days.
我必须去
I have to go,
这事都怪我告诉他
This is my fault.
我们也去
We are going.
大家一起带上武器和食物
All of us get weapons and food,
别告诉任何人
Tell no one.
我们的孩子去找氏族了
Our children have gone to clan.
你们允许的吗？
You let them?
他们是偷偷去的
They did not ask.
我派战士去追他们
I will get the warriors to go after them.
我们不可能搜遍整个海洋
We cannot search the whole sea.
而且我们需要战士来守护幼鲲圣餐仪式
We need the warriors defend for calf's communion.
以防恶魔船来袭
If the de
可我儿子现在孤身在外
My boy is out there by himself.
等他有了他的下落 自然就回来了
He will come back when he hears it.
这是他要走的路
This is his path.
瞧瞧他做了什么
Look at what he did.
杰克 你儿子继承了先人的智慧(血脉)
Jake, the strength of the ancestors runs in your son's veins.
这点你必须相信
You must trust that.
水之道  永无止境
The Real Water has no beinning and no way.
大海就是你的家园
The sea is your home.
在你出生之前
Before your brith.
你注定是死神终结者
You're the Terminator of Death.
那个江湖人称“魅影骑士”的人 他在哪里？
Where is the one that called Toruk Makto?
大海里面有多少鱼
How many fish are in the sea?
一拍二
One plus two.
天空中有多少鸟
How many birds are in the sky?
一拍二拍三......
One plus two plus three...
琪莉 这样
Kiri, come on.
你请求伊娃让我再高一点
You could ask Eywa let me a little bit taller.
顺便让她把我变得更蓝些
Maybe even a little bit more blue.
不
No.
曾几何时 我一心想着救你的命 无赖
I was busy saving you life scoundrel.
那怕是高一点点
Just a little bit.
几厘米也好啊
A couple centimeters.
她是母神 她无所不能
She's the old mother, she can do anything.
你本来就很完美 无须改变
You are perfect just the way you are.
来吧 淘气鬼
Come on, monkey boy.
所以下一步...
So the next thing...
...我要学会骑掠波翼龙
...is I'm going to learn how to ride a Skimwing.
所以你可以成为一名猛士来保护我们
So you can become a mighty warrior to protect us.
尽管你个子.....
For all...
嘿 狗打架不论大小
Hey, it's not the size of the dog in the fight.
而是论规模
it's the size of the fight in the dog.
这是什么？
What is it?
快点
Come on.
跑！
Run!
快 快
Go, go.
蜘蛛！
Spider!
我在这里 混蛋
Over here, asshole.
来抓我啊
Come on.
嘿 童子军
Hey, scout.
这边啊 你们这些杂碎
This way, you bastards.
小心你们的狗屎
Watch your shit.
有本事来抓我
That's all you've got.
见鬼
Shit!
放开我！操
Let's me go! Fuck.
小子 省省气吧
Boy, save your energy.
当心那把刀
Be careful with that knife.
就这点能耐
That's all you.
别伤到自己了
Don't get hurt.
空气呼吸器
Air breather.
我们得飞了
We've to flight.
大功告成
Bring off.
闪电飞行
Lightning flight.
蓝1
Blue one.
我们出发
Let's set off.
图克
Tuk.
我们被包围了
They're locking us in.
Pick up the weapons.
抄起武器
你姐姐在哪？
Where's your sister?
她打水去了
She went for water.
琪莉在哪里？蛛蛛呢？
Where's Kiri? Where's spider?
爹
Dad.
蜘蛛在哪里？
Where's spider?
他被捉走了
They took him.
那个蓝色上校捉走了他
The blue colonel took him.
接住他
Catch him.
冷静
Be calm.
别害怕
No fear.
杰克·萨利
Jack Sully.
带女孩们走 立刻
Thke the girls and go now.
你不走 我不会走
I'll not go without you.
不 蜘蛛已落在他们手上
No, they got spider.
我们再无法阻止他们
There's nothing holding them back.
你见识过他们的手段 再不走这些人都会没命
You see what they can do, these people will die.
你不能赶我走
You cannot ask this.
丈夫 我做不到
Husband, I cannot.
这是唯一的办法
This is the only way.
杰克·萨利......
Jake Sully...
快滚出来
Show yourself.
你得走了 你得马上就走
You gotta go, you gotta go right now.
带你妹妹去躲起来
Take your
快去
Go.
你要留下我绝不走
If you stay I stay.
老娘要开荤 大开杀戒
I will kill many.
不管发生任何事 你都不能开弓
Whatever happens do not raise that bow.
你向我发誓
You swear to me.
我知道他就在这
I know he's here.
给他传话
Give it to him.
他是梅卡伊纳人 是我们的族人
He is the Metkayina, he is one of us.
他是我们的人
他是我们的族人
He's one of us.
放火龙
Burn something dragon.
呼唤4队
Call Team 4.
朝第二村庄投放一些燃烧弹
Lay down some incendiary in the second village
收到 正在切换燃烧弹
Copy! Switching incendiary.
我要杰克·萨利
I want Jake Sully.
停手 停手 不 不
Stop, stop, no, no.
别开火 别开火
Hold your fire, hold your fire.
快停手
Stop.
停火
No fire.
收到 马上执行
Copy, bring it on.
这就是我要走的路 兄弟
This is my path, brother.
上校
Colonel.
下士
Corporal.
带我走
Take me.
放过我的家人和这些人
You leave my family and these people alone.
光带你一个不够
Not good enough.
你夫人也要带走
Gonna need the Mrs too.
你要的是我
You get me.
你俩我都要 否则我把这个地方夷为平地
Both of you, or I'll hammer this place flat.
包括这里的孕妇 孩子
Pregnant ladies, kids,
我会把老太婆那副瘦骨嶙峋的小腿骨打爆 把它扔到酒桶的后面
I'll blow grandma's skinny shin throw the back of the hooch cask.
但我毫不在乎
But I just don't care.
他们只想干掉所有人 虏走你们中的侦察兵
They're just dying to waste everybody and take some scouts.
来真的吗？
Really?
我们奉陪到底
We doing this.
当我手臂放下来 你和你的小甜点就会小命不保
When I drop my arm you and your new cupcake will die.
你会连渣不剩
You in particular die a lot.
我死了 这里所有人也别想活命
I die, everybody here dies.
也许吧 但你想把我们杀光 可没那么容易
Maybe, I think you can get some of us
也许我们的投弹手开始动手 你们的武装直升机还呆在机库里
Maybe our bomber into action, your gunships hesitate.
因为我们旗鼓相当 然后
Because we all look the same, and then,
等你求饶的时候
when you're begging for your life.
我会剥了你的头皮
I'll scalp you.
该死的下士
The damm corporal,
我不知道你是真聪明还是想找死
I don't know if you're smart or just shit nuts.
老实说 我从来没觉得你有多聪明
You never struck me as all that smart.
我需要你保证海洋之间的族人安全
I need your word marine to marine safety for these people.
烧了他们所有人 夸里奇
Burn them all, Quaritch.
我们的达成交易吗？
Do we have a deal?
我默认了
Dumb.
真是头猪你发誓
What a pig you swear?
雅各布
Jacob.
Turn around.
转过来
走吧
Move.
我们走吧 快点
Let's go. Come on.
再会 萨利夫人
On another time Mrs Sully.
祝你好运
Good luck.
有什么发现吗？
What do we got?
长官 我们发现了大批斑溪兽骑手闯入我们的领地
Ma'am, we have a big incursion Banshee riders inbound.
明白了 朝他们开火
I see that so light them up.
无法开火 长官 武器已被锁死
I can't, ma'am, weapons locked out.
他们都有国际航空联合会徽章
They all have IFAF badges.
扩展它
Expand it.
锁定六七个目标
Go on six seven targets.
给我站好 你们这些白痴
Steht aufrecht, ihr ldioten
不要怂
Zeigt keine Furcht.
现在按住他
Hold on now.
滚开！
Get out!
我们走吧
Let's go.
杰克
Jake.
快点
Hurry!
我们走
Let's go.
杰克
Jake.
进去
Come in.
总算不辱使命 将军
This is your request, genera.
杰克·萨利 “魅影骑士”本人
Jake Sully, Toruk Makto himself.
你给他们分发枪械还不够
It's not enough for you to hand out guns.
你还把敌人带进我们的防御阵地
You gotta bring hostiles inside the perimeter.
不太明白她意思
Get the little.
冷静
Calmness.
不是敌人 是盟友
Not hostiles, allies.
我向您引见一下这位是芒克万族的瓦琅·扎希克
General Ardmore, I'd like you to meet Varang Zahik of the Mangkwan.
不如让我把话说得再明白点 夸里奇上校
Let me make this very clear, colonel Quaritch.
我要把这些野蛮人通通护赶出我的基地
I want every one of these savages escorted off my base a sap.
包括你的小情人
Including you little Missy over there.
别犯傻了 将军
Don't be a jackass, general.
我们胜利了
Take the win.
因为我们有这些人
We got these people.
和媒体
and the media.
哇......
Woha...
准备好了吗？
Ready?
我们走吧
Let's go.
可能会有一点痛
Just feel this a little bit.
别动
Hold still.
很好
Good.
听着 看这个
Listen, look this.
帕亚坎
Payakan.
人们说大海能把你冲刷干净
The people say the sea washes you clean.
帕亚坎
Payakan.
-是洛阿克 -是他
-It's Lo'ak. -It's him.
洛阿克！
Lo'ak!
就是他
It's him.
洛阿克
Lo'ak.
在哪儿停下！
Stop over there!
洛阿克 洛阿克
Lo'ak. Lo'ak.
提蕾娅！
Tsireya!
他们还说
They also say,
你有幸看到水生智慧种族——冰海天使
if you see the deep ones, the Clione.
他们的灵魂会来审判你
Their spirits sent to judge you.
洛阿克
Lo'ak.
走走走
Go, go, go.
洛阿克 洛阿克 洛阿克
Lo'ak, Lo'ak, Lo'ak.
提蕾娅
Tsrieya.
谢谢万灵之母
Thank you great mother.
好了 让他休息一下
Come on, let him rest.
让他松口气
Let him go.
做梦都没想到你们会追来
Can't believe you guys came after me.
我朋友的路就是我的路
My friend's path is my path.
-这是你的鲲姐吗？-是的
-Is this your sister? -Yes.
帕亚坎呢？她听到他了吗？
What about Payakan? Does she hear him?
他就在附近 他马上就来了
He is close, he is coming now.
有什么发现吗？
So what you've got?
这是我的硒元素 它寄存在他的体内
This is my selenium that's living inside his body.
等等 你是说他的体内有东西？
Wait, there's something living inside of him?
对
Yes.
这是一种内共生体 它以某种方法调节离子的活动......
It's an endosymbiont somehow moderating the ion...
且慢
Stop.
我对它怎么工作没兴趣
I don't need to know how it works.
我只关心我们能否克隆它
I just need to know if we can duplicate it.
放我出去 你个混蛋 马上！
Let me out, you jerk, now!
我已经吩咐那些带手套的家伙暂时别来打扰你
I told those rubber glove pukes to lay off you for a while.
杰克在哪里？
Where's Jake?
他现在被关在他该呆的地方
He's locked up where he belongs here.
我给你带了汉堡包
I brought you a burger.
最好他别受伤
Better not hurt.
他不再是你生命中的依靠
He's not part of your life anymore.
你现在跟我在一起
You with me now.
我是你爹
I'm your father.
我爹死了
My father is dead.
你就是他的替身而已
This is something made up that he gave his memories here.
不对 不对 我还是我
No, no, I'm still me.
我查过了 你看
I checked, there look.
迈尔斯·夸里奇上校
Colonel Miles Quaritch.
我理解
I see it.
我们根本没有机会好好谈话
No way have a chance to talk too much.
那时候 我们一块呆在丛林里 不过......
When we were out in the bush together, but...
我得跟你说声谢谢
I gotta thank you.
我是说 是你从沉船里拖了我一把
I mean you hauled me out of a sunken.
你救了我一命
You saved my life.
是的 我当初就不该去救你
Yeah, sure wish I hadn't done that.
也许你说得对
Maybe that's true.
也许在你心底里并非这样想
Maybe deep down it isn't either way.
我欠你的
I owe you.
还有我必须.....跟你说件事
And I gotta...tell you that.
伙计 我为你骄傲
Man I'm proud of you.
你是个了不起的孩子
You're amazing kid.
有胆识又聪明
You got guts, smarts.
而且儿子 你有一颗狮子般的心
And son, you got the heart of a lion.
你有我当年的风范 嗯
I see myself in you, uh.
我实话告诉你 我了解你就像了解你妈妈一样
I tell you I really see you, that's your mother.
她嘛 嗯 很彪悍
She was uh... ferocious.
难以相处
Tough to live with
但我爱她
I love her.
而伙计 你知道她爱你吗？
And man did she love you.
你娘干过最困难的事就是那天登上武装直升机奔赴战场
Hardest thing she ever did was boarding that gunship that day going into battle.
留下她的小宝贝
Leaving her little baby behind.
你娘她是个英雄 儿子
Your mom died a hero, son.
你也觉得是吧
You got that in you too.
无论如何 我来这儿可不是为了打酱油的
Anyway I didn't come down here take a trip down memoty lane.
我主要是想告诉你
I just came by to tell you.
要是你需要我
If you need me.
我哪能不愿意
I'm willing for you.
能把它给我吗？
Can I keep it in.
饿了吃点东西
Eat thing when hungry.
兄弟
Brother.
见到你我很高兴
Lch bin froh, dich zu sehen.
我看到了你 兄弟
I see you, brother.
这是什么？怎么了？
What is it? What's wrong?
这是......
Es ist...
过得很惨
Sehr schimm.
你没找到你的族群吗？
Didn't you find you birth clan.
找到了
Habe ich.
但只有一个人活了下来
Aber nur eine hat uberlebt.
我叫塔塔克
Ich bin Ta'nok.
看看他们对我做了什么
Seht, was sie mir angetan haben.
他们朝我开枪
Sie schossen auf mich.
把我双眼弄瞎了
Haben mich geblendet.
瞧瞧 那些天空人对我做了些什么
Seht, was mir die Himmelsmenschen angetan haben.
图鲲们已陆续抵达
Tulkuns are alreacy coming in.
不过直到后天日食之后
But the aggregation doesn't peak until the eclipse...
...这种集合才会达到顶峰
...which is the day after tomorrow.
那是我们袭击的最佳时机
That's when we hit.
不行 不行
No, no.
接着说
Hold on, no.
不行 你是说要进行大规模屠杀
No, you're talking about wholesale slaughter.
把数百人干掉 摧毁整个地区
Hundreds killed entire parts just wiped out.
要的就是这种效果
That's the beauty of the idea.
短短一天我们就能吹嘘一年
We'll feel a year's gloater in just one day.
这些都是有智慧的生灵
These are intelligent soulful beings.
你是哪位？
Who are you?
英格曼·雷因生物学家
Ingerman Rein biologist.
这些生物他们有文化
These creatures they have culture.
有音乐 有他们各自的名字
They have music, they have names for each other.
这是有组织的 有目的的一场集合
This is organized, this aggregation is deliberate.
这是一次精神聚会......
It's a spiritual gathering...
放低你的架子 卡弗
Get off your high horse, Carver.
我们都达成了协议
We all made our deals.
不 我拒绝报名参加这个项目
No, I do not sign up for this.
加文博士 加文博士
Dr.Garvin, Dr.Garvin.
谢谢你
Thank you.
我记住了你的抗议
Your protest has been noted.
-你记住了？-没错
-Has been noted? -Yes.
潜艇小队和快艇你们从警戒线出发
Sub teams and fast boats you guys will form a cordon.
你驾驶家族车队驶到此处...
You drive the family groups in here...
...形成一道天然屏障 阻挡通往岛屿的去路
...where it forms a natural choke point against the islands.
我从没忘记
I haven't forgotten.
上校 继续努力！
Colonel, work on!
别拥挤！
Don't crowd!
武器 先生
Weapon, sir.
结束祈祷吧 杰克
End of the grace, Jack.
明天六点正
Zero six tomorrow.
错误占据了内心
Wrong latch the heart.
或者蹲着输
Or lost by squat.
塞尔弗里奇说这是他们更想看到的
Selfridge says it's a better optic.
是的 你会成为那些权贵们的傀儡
Yes, you'll be a good dog for the suits.
这不是我当下关心的事
This isn't about now.
我当下关心的是我和你之间
It's about me and you.
关于一个背叛我信任的海军陆战队员
About a marine that betrayed my trust.
关于我失去了男人和女人的事
About the men and women I lost.
你是他的替身
Dead man's memories.
迈尔斯·夸里奇不在了
Miles Quaritch is gone.
你现在自由了
You're free.
And there is a world out there.
外面有一个世界
这些事情 那些权贵们永远不会懂
These things that those suits will never understand.
纳美人管它们叫“感知”
The Na'vi call them "kame".
我懂他们那个意思
I understand what they call it.
那就学着去“感知”
Then learn to see.
Connect to something qreater than you...
去接触更高级的文明...
...一种你无法想象的高级文明
...greater than anything, you've ever know.
让我们“感知”这个世界
Let's see this world,
“感知”你自己
see yourself.
我感知到你了
I see you.
六点正
In zero six.
上次我俘获了两个
Last time I got tow.
但他们是村子里最丑的
Yeah, but they were the ugliest ones in the village.
手放在墙上！
Hands on the wall!
干得好
Done good.
锁起他
Lock him.
没事 只是想看一下你们
It's nothing just want to watch you guys.
你觉得怎么样？
What do you think?
好吧 我有博士学位 还搞不定它吗？
Okay, you're got a PhD. How hard to me?
停一下
Stop.
你太牛了！
You're so amazing!
瞧瞧这个！
Check this out！
怎么了？ 小美人
What's up, cutie?
她看上我了
She wants me.
嘿 嘿 给我
Hey, hey, give me.
夸里奇 夸里奇上校
Quaritch. Colonel Quaritch.
我们就是火焰 敬灰烬族！
We are the fire, to Mangkwan!
我们就是火焰！干杯！
We are the fire! Cheers!
夸里奇！
Quaritch!
夸里奇......
Quaritch...
哨子 别出声  杰克·萨利在哪里？
Make no sound, whistle, where is Jake Sully?
所有的妻子都忠于她的男人
All wife loyal to her man.
快说 不然我割了你
Speak, or I cut.
在哪？我最后问你一遍
Where? I will not ask again.
不 且慢
No, no, wait.
别杀我
Wait.
在营地里
At the camp.
他被关在一个兽笼里
A cave where an animal.
带我去
Take me there.
走！哪一边？
Move! Which way?
嘿 亲爱的
Hey, dear.
追上她
Get after her.
别让她跑了
Don't let her run away.
抓住她
Catch her.
快快快
Go, go, go.
驾
Ride.
发生什么事？
What happened?
杰克
Jake.
将军？
General?
现在没空 我遇到麻情了
Not now, I have a situation.
不是 我遇到麻烦了
No, I have a situation.
那孩子跑了
The kid is loose.
我需要他活着回来
And I need him back alive.
朝她开火！
Light her up!
迈尔斯·索图罗 “蜘蛛”通缉公告
Miles"Spider"Socorro C:ONTACT SEC-OPS
闪开 伙计们 我要砸了它 砸了它
Out of the way guys, move it, move it.
快闪开 伙计们！
Out of the way, Guys!
快点！阻止他！
Be quick! Stop him!
我要动手啦
Let me do it.
快走 杰克
Go, Jake.
朝他开火！
Light him up!
倒车！
Reversing!
好的
Yeah.
火力攻击 别让他跑了！
Light him up! Don't let him get away!
好的 他跑掉了
Yes, he has run away.
安全伴我行
Safe with me.
我在干什么？我在干什么？
What am I doing? What am I doing?
我的扩议现在还记住吗？混帐东西
Is my protest noted now? fuckers.
杰克
Jake.
这边走
This way.
走 赶紧！
Go, hurry up!
这边！
This way!
雷因·加文 海洋生物学家
Rein Garvin, biologist.
来吧
Come on.
呃 我得说
uh, I gotta say,
我对你的英雄事迹仰慕已久 犹如滔滔江水
I'm a real big fan of everything you've done.
我正在努力找他们一点麻烦
I'm working a little hard find them now.
我们就在这儿 别出声！
We right there. Shut up!
有什么计划？
What's the plan?
我们只能见步行步了
This is as far as I got.
也就是说你没有计划
But then there's no plan.
开个玩笑
Just kidding.
走吧
Come on.
走走走
Go, go, go.
你为什么要这么做？
Why are you doing this?
They're gonna to massive Tulkun hunt the day after tomorrow.
他们计划在后天进行一场图鲲大猎杀
你必须摧毁他们所有的舰艇
You need to hit every ship they've got.
幼鲲圣餐仪式
The calf's communion.
你必须阻止他们 只有你能够做到
You've got to stop them, you're the only one who can.
走吧
Come on.
萨塔 嘘......
Sata, shh...
我们走吧
Let's go.
走 出去！ 快 快
Go, get out! Go, go.
快 离开这儿
Go, get out of here.
搞什么鬼
What the fuck！
利马16号 有个目标被困在一辆车后面
Lima one six, there's a subject pinned down behind a vehicle.
目标已锁定
The subject has been lock.
切换导弹干掉他
Switch missiles take him out.
明白 导弹切换中
Got it. Switching missiles.
嘿 还记得我吗？
Hey, remember me?
对了 两匹劣马跑出来了
That's right, two bad horses get out.
我不需要这些玩意
I don't need this shit.
你要干什么？
What are you gonna do?
开枪打我吗？
Do you gonna shoot me?
这孩子拒绝使用空气呼吸器 他挡住了我的镜头
The kid can't with the air breather, he's blocking my shot.
别开枪！告诉马克斯别开枪！
Don't shoot! Tell Max not to shoot!
告诉16号 这里是蓝1
Tell one six, blue one,
停止开火 盯紧16号
Hold your fire, keep visual on one six.
16号停止开火！
One six hold your fire!
在当前位置待命
Stand by at that position.
嗯 你不会向我开枪的 知道为什么吗？
Yeah, you're not gonna shoot me, you know why?
因为你不行 哈哈
Because you can't, haha.
现在你能拿我怎样 你可以亲我的屁股
Now you can do though, you can kiss my ass.
没错
Yeah.
来吧 杰克 快走
Come on, Jake, go.
你做了什么？
What did you do?
来吧 走吧走吧 快点
Come on, go, go, come on.
他正往西面移动 目标仍被锁定 但射击点被遮挡
He's moving west, maintain a target lock, the shot is not clear.
嘿 跟着我
Hey, stay on me.
跟在我身边
Stay close to me.
我不想再玩这个游戏了
I'm not gonna play this game.
利马16号 放手一搏
Lima one six take your shot.
别别别 别开枪！
No, no, no, don't shoot!
I hear that, hold your fire.
我听到了 别开火
快快快
Go, go, go.
利马16号......
Lima one six...
利马16号 获准开火 武器自由
Lima one six, you are cleared hot, weapons free.
无法锁定目标 正在调整方向
Unable lock subject, ciming around.
他绕回去了
He's go back around.
这边走
This way.
这里是蓝1
This is bule one.
检查你的火力
Check your fire.
利马16号 你已获准开火
Lima one six, you're cleared hot.
16号已就位
One six stand by.
走开！
Go away!
我的杰克 走吧
My Jake, go.
奈蒂莉！
Neytiri!
亲爱的！
Baby!
我不知道是该亲你还是骂你
I don't know whether to kiss you or gallop you.
废话少说
You waste time.
上吧 咱们走
Come on, let's go.
走吧
Let's go!
随便找个地方着陆吧
Land anywhere.
我得去撒泡尿
I gotta take a urinate.
你们着陆得可真及时
You guys landed just in time.
有什么事吗？
What is it?
为什么要停下来？
Why are we stopping?
这种裤子连个苍蝇都飞不进去
They didn't even put a fly inside
真是愚蠢的设计
That's just dumb.
好主意
Good idea.
先喝水 再尿小溪里
Drink first, then piss in this stream.
什么事 杰克？
What is it, Jake?
我错了
I was wrong.
我们无法保护他
We can't protect him.
我得把这件外套脱下来
I gotta take this stuff off.
痒死了！
It's so itchy!
夸里奇有了这个女人 无论我们身在何处 他都能找到我们
Quaritch has this woman, she can find us wherever we go.
他们要逮捕他
They will get him.
他们要研究他
They will study him.
而当人类可以呼吸这儿的空气
And when humans can breathe our air.
到那时我将会把它传播到全世界
Then I will spread it across this world.
而且我将会毁掉森林 海洋 所有东西...
And I will destroy the forests, the oceans, everything...
...就像在地球上那样
...just like on earth.
到那时纳美人将不复存在
Then the Na'vi people will be gone.
图鲲也不复存在
The Tulkun will be gone.
我不能让这种事情发生
And I can't let that happen.
你们饿吗？我饿死了
Are you hungry? I'm starving.
你是对的
You were right.
这事必须要去做
It has to be done.
杰克
Jake.
他救了你的命
He saved your life.
我们别无他法
This is the only way.
蜘蛛
Spider.
过来
Come here.
出什么事了？
What's up?
怎么了？
What is it?
她就来
She's coming.
我们走吧
Let's go.
嘿 等一下 我们得放放水
Hey, stop for a second, we gotta take a leak.
就附近吧
Just stay close.
我们要去哪里？
Where are we going?
安静
Be quiet.
所以 你有什么想说的吗？
So do you have something to talk?
过来 跑 快
Come here, run, come on.
看看
Look!
这块石头
That's the one.
跪在上面
Kneel on it.
不
No.
跪在这
Kneel here.
拜托了
Please.
杰克 拜托 停下来
Jake, please stop.
对不起
I'm sorry.
别动
Don't move.
拜托
Please.
你用不着这么做
You don't have to do this.
别这样
Please.
万灵之母 你在吗？
Great mother, are you here?
你不能这么做
You can't to do this.
指引我的手
Guide my hands.
请别这么做
Please don't do this.
停下
Stop.
拜托 停下来 拜托
Please, stop, please.
别看着我
Don't look at me.
原谅我 儿子
Forgive me, son.
我会乖的
I'll be good.
愿你的灵魂归于伊娃
May your spirit go to Eywa.
我保证
I promise.
愿你的身体归于森林
May your body return to the forest.
求你
Please.
维持神圣的平衡
To preserve the great balance.
May the ancestors welcome you.
愿先人欢迎你
不要
No.
愿先人拥抱你
May the ancestors hold you.
愿你可唱自己的歌
May you sing your song.
我知道 我现在就得归于伊娃
I know I have to go to Eywa now.
没事的
It's okay.
但是...
But...
...你是否...
...do you...
...你是否还爱我？
...do you still love me.
全心全意爱你
With all my heart.
我的杰克 我的杰克
My Jake, my Jake.
我看到你了
I see you.
无论发生什么事 都不应该走这条路
Whatever happens it won't be this way.
我们会找到其他路的
And we will find another way.
我爸爸知道 在他的心里...
My dad knew in his heart...
...通往目标的道路始终只有一条
...there was ever one path.
无论你怎么想象 他都是那样
No matter how you imagine himself.
身为父亲
As a father,
身为丈夫
as a husband,
总有一天你会回来的
sooner or later you're back on it.
你好啊 老友
Hello, old friend.
托鲁克也爱我爹
Toruk loved my father.
他知道他们共同联手才会更强大
He knew they were greater together.
当他们起飞时 注定是一场腥风血雨
That when they flew there would be blood
他来了
He is coming.
拜见魅影骑士！
See Turnk Makto!
拜见！
See!
别这样... 请你们... 都起来吧
No, just... please stand...stand up.
请起吧
Please stand up.
亲爱的
Baby.
杰克
Jake.
请
Please.
好了 没事的
Ok, it's ok.
你们即刻动身 尽快前往所有的部落告知他们
Go now, to all the clans within the days right tell them.
就说魅影骑士召唤他们
Tell that Turok Makto calls to them.
你告诉他们
You tell them.
这一天已经到来
The day has come.
于是战争就这样发生了
And so it came to pass.
魅影骑士归来了
The Toruk Makto returned.
我爹再次团结了部落
My father united the clans once again.
发表了意义重大的演讲
He made the great speeches.
多支箭凑在一块是无法被折断的
Many arrows togerher cannot be broken.
我们是无法被折断的
We cannot be broken.
但他知道只团结族人还远远不够
But he knew that it wasn't enough.
伟大的族长
Great patriarch.
智慧的长老们
Wise elders.
天空人要来了
The sky people are coming.
没错 就在今天
Yes, today.
此时此刻 他们要屠杀我们的图鲲家族
Right now to kill our Tulkun families.
我恳请你们 与我们并肩作战
I beg you, fight with us.
她说：我们尊重“魅影骑士”
She says we respect Toruk Makto,
但我们有传统的习俗
but our ways are ancient.
我们坚信杀戮只会带来更多杀戮
We believe that killing will only bring more killing,
一旦开始将永无宁日
in an endless expanding spiral.
听我说
Hear my words.
天空人绝不会善罢甘休
The Sky people will never stop.
Not until the last of the Tulkun is hunted.
直到图鲲被猎杀殆尽
洛阿克
Lo'ak.
我兄弟必须向议会发言
Mein Bruder muss zum Rat sprechen.
帕尔坎 去吧
Payakan! Geh!
这不是你的错
Du darfst nicht hier sein.
停下......
Stop...
洛阿克 你在干什么？
Lo'ak, what are you doing?
爹......等等
Dad...wait.
但你不能呆在这
But you can't be here.
我是塔塔克的兄弟
I am brother of To'nok.
我有权说话
I have a right to speak.
洛阿克说的是事实 你必须听他说
Lo'ak speaks the truth, you must listen.
提蕾娅
Tsireya.
长老说他的兄弟是被驱逐者
She says his brother is outcast.
这里轮不到你说话
You have no standing here.
要是他是被驱逐者
If he is outcast.
那我也是被驱逐者
Then I am outcast.
还有我也是被驱逐者
And I am outcast.
女儿 闭嘴
Daughter, shut up.
不
No.
你再也感知不到我了
You will never see me again.
而我和我的兄弟都是被驱逐者
And I and my brother are outcast.
奥农
Aonung.
而我们同样是被驱逐者
And we are also outcast.
长老说你可以发言了
She says you may speak.
请听我说
Hear my words.
我兄弟本想回到他的出生部落那里去保护它
My brother returned to his brith clan to defend it.
然而他的部落却惨遭恶魔船的灭绝
But his clan was wiped out by the demon ships.
只有塔塔克逃过一劫
Only Ta'nok survived.
因为她进行了反击
Because she fought back.
来吧
Come on.
天啊
My god.
塔塔克说：我要替死去的母亲和死去的那些幼鲲说话
To'nok says, I speak for the dead mothers and the dead calves.
我要替我的族人和所有的灵魂说话
I speak for my people and all our souls.
永别了！
Gone forever.
她说我是我们家族里幸存的瞎子目击者
She says I am the blind witness to our end.
塔塔克说 图鲲之道必须改变
To'nok says, the Tulkun way must change,
帕尔坎就是活生生的例子
Payakan showed us.
我们必须要反抗！
We must fight!
我们必须反抗！
长老的意思是什么？
What did she say?
他们还没决定好
They will decide.
看看画面中一切
Look at all of this.
我是说他们的数量众多
I mean there's hundreds of them look
看看这些老古董
Look at all these old ones.
老的很好
Old is good.
它们从未停止生长
They never stop growing.
也就是说它们蕴含大量的“甘露”
Which means more Amrita.
大家再看看这个
Look at this one.
她足足有一百米长
She must be a hundred meters.
这种作战指示怎能少了我
You're briefing without me.
我认为你们疏忽了
An oversight I assume.
不 我们并非疏忽
No, we're not a oversight.
在你和萨利搞砸之后 你就玩完了 上校
After your fiasco with Sully you're done, colonel.
You're confined to base pending an investigation.
你已被限制在基地内 等待调查
这永远不会困扰我 因为我需要翻身
It never gonna bother that I need to roll.
萨利会在那里
Sully will be there.
也就是说 蜘蛛同样会在那里
Which means that spider will be there
别指望他了
Don't look at him.
他的一只脚已踏进了禁闭室
He's one step away from the brig himself.
别告诉我需要指望我
Don't tell me, need to look at me.
你要干嘛？打电话给你爹？
What are you gonna do? call daddy?
你是说主席吗？
You mean the chairman?
够了
It's enough.
我仍能胜任这项任务
I can still complete this mission.
瞧瞧你
Look at you.
你简直是你军装的耻辱！
You're a disgrace to your uniform!
假如你还记得你的军装代表什么
Assuming you remember what your uniform is.
你被禁足了！上校
You're grounded, colonel!
无限期！
Permanently!
你为什么来这里？ 丫头
Why are you here, girl?
祈祷 酋长
To pray, sheikh.
不 孩子
No, child.
为什么你要来装腔作态？
Why did you come pose?
大概你是等这个时机
Perhaps it was for this moment.
因为只有被伊娃眷顾之人才能召唤战士之母
Only a chosen one may call upon the warrior mother.
酋长
Sheikh.
你在宫缩呢
You're having contractions.
我有种不祥预感......我们会葬身于这场战争
I fear we will...we will not survive this.
琪莉
Kiri.
听我说
Hear my words.
或许你能为这场战争做些什么
Perhaps something you can do.
而且你必须要做
And you must do it.
你有一颗强大的心
You have a strong heart.
是的
Yeah.
我也想去作战
I want to fight too.
不行 这里需要你
No, I need you here.
除非你能保证自身安全 否则我无法答应你
I can't do this unless I know you can keep safe.
无论发生什么事你都要坚守岗位
You keep your post no matter what happens.
你理解我意思吗？
You read me?
交给我吧 长官
Let me try sir.
万一爹娘有什么冬瓜豆腐
If your father and I do not return.
你就带上蜘蛛和丫头们...
You take spider and the girls...
...走得越远越快越好
...and you go as far and as fast as you can.
靠他大爷
Holy shit.
将军 这种磁通量超出了范围
General, this flux is off the scale.
我们要远离那个恐怖的磁力
Keep a wide radius from that flux devil,
否则那东西会把你脸皮撕下来
that thing will rip your face off.
收到 将军 正在避开它
Received general, I am avoiding it.
好了 伙计们 我们先来热热身吧
All right, boys, let's burn some fat.
咱们上吧 放手大干
Let's go, let's do this.
潜艇部队 获取网络
Dunker team, get web.
大家都准备好了吗？动手吧
Everybody ready? Let's do it!
看到敌人了吗？
See any hostiles?
没有动静
Negative no movement.
这些大家伙都在忙着他们的事
And the big guys are just doing their thing.
鱼儿已经游进桶里了
Fish swan into the barrel.
稳住
Hold.
坚持住
Hang on.
没见着公鲲也没见着大母鲲
There's no bulls and no big females.
长老也没见着
There's no elders.
别灰心 各位
Hold up, everybody.
长官 我接收到一个巨大的图鲲信号
Sir, I got a big signal to Tulkun.
巨型的
Big ones.
一大群巨型的 各种各样的图鲲入境
Lots of big ones, multiple Tulkun inbound.
斯科斯比 我记得你跟我说过它们没有攻击性
Scorsby, I thought you told me they're not aggressive.
所以 他们没有
So, they have not.
正常来说
That's the norm.
帕亚坎 听我发令
Payakan, ich ubernehme die Fuhrung.
遵命 酋长
Ja, Matriarchin.
我看不见它们了
I lost visual.
伙计们 他们正在战斗
Dude, they're fighting.
是啊 是啊
Yeah, yeah.
现在
Now.
杀啊！
Kill!
咱们上！
Let's go!
杀啊！
Kill!
去死吧！
Go to hell!
当心！
Watch out!
准备武器！
Ready weapons!
开火！
Open fire!
把鱼叉瞄准他们！把鱼叉瞄准他们！
Put the harpoons at them! Put the harpoons at them!
发射！
Shoot!
攻击它！
Hit it!
当心！
Watch out!
干得好 杰克
Well done, Jack.
兄弟 兄弟
Bro, bro.
好啊 好啊
Yeah, yeah.
杰克！
Jake!
是灰烬族
It's the Ash.
全体待命！
All stand by!
这支是我们的盟军
This one is our allies.
他们可能配有国际航空联合会微章
They might have IFAF badges.
将军 感谢您给我这个将功补过的机会
General, thanks for giving me the opprtunity to contribute and achieve results.
不
No.
他们赢不了了
They can't wim.
他们会死的
They will die.
琪莉
Kiri.
-阻止她 -琪莉
-Stop her. -Kiri.
琪莉 停住
Kiri, stop.
琪莉 停住 停住
Kiri, stop, stop.
立刻回到避难所去
Get back to the shelter right now.
这儿不安全
It's not safe here.
我必须呼唤“万灵之母‘
I have to call the great mother.
要是你在水下这样干 会要了你小命的
If you do that underwater, it will kill you.
你不能这样干
You can't do this.
图克 你不能待在外面
Tuk, you can't stay out there.
现在就走
Right now go.
回去
Get back.
琪莉 等等！
Kiri, wait!
停住！ 别走
Stop！No.
琪莉 停住
Kiri, stop.
琪莉！
Kiri!
来吧
Come on.
别 等等
No, wait.
天啊
My god.
图克 你必须回去
Tuk, You must keep back.
我是认真的
I mean it.
洛阿克 快点
Lo'ak, come on.
别跟着我
Do not follow me.
快来
Come on.
洛阿克 他们来了
Lo'ak, they're coming.
跟我们一起战斗吧
Fight with us.
我们必须保护母亲
Wir mussen die Mutter verteidigen.
No, 我要和她待一起
No, I'll stay with her.
来吧
Come on.
圣母
Holy mother.
听我说
Hear my words.
求您帮帮我们
Please help us.
我感觉到你
I feel you.
你是我们唯一的希望
You are our only hope.
不
No.
拜托了
Please.
我们需要你
We need you.
别不理我
Don't push me away.
我们希望......
We holp...
不要 求你 求你了
No, please, please.
不要 不要 不要
No, no, no.
淘气鬼
Monkey boy.
我们开始吧
Let's do this.
来吧
Come on.
加油
开火！
Fire!
我恳求你
I beg you.
拜托
Please.
别啊 求你了
No, please.
我们的族人正在遇难
The people are dying.
拜托
Please.
别
No.
图克
Tuk.
一道......光
One...light.
我们可以做到
We can do this.
所以我们永不放弃
So we never quits.
加把劲 一起走
Come on, let's go.
图克
Tuk.
加把劲
Come on.
万灵之母
Great mother.
救救我们吧！我们恳求您！
Help us! We beg you!
我们的族人正在遇难
The people are dying.
我呼唤战士之母
I call the warrior mother.
唯有您能拯救我们
You are only holp.
开火
Fire.
不......
No...
就是他 快抓住他！
That's him, get him!
骑手们 跟我来！
Riders, follow me!
萨塔！
Sata!
好姑娘
Girl girl.
你没事吧？
You okay?
没事
Yeah.
琪莉呢？
Where's Kiri?
她倒下了
She came down.
躲避危险
Get to safety.
别进攻了
Do not attack.
我们完蛋了
We're done.
爹！
Dad!
洛阿克！
Lo'ak!
爹！
Dad!
你还好吧？
You okay?
好了 我扶住你了
Okay, I got you.
酋长！
Sheikh!
待在这别动
Stay here.
我要回去找她
I'm going bsck for her.
你不能把我一个人丢在这里
You can't leave me alone here.
萨塔 等等
Sata, wait.
我快不行了
I am dying.
不 你死不了
No, you can not.
我怎么老是要跟我斗气
Why must you always argue.
我...我不行了
I am...I am dying.
但临死之前我要把这个孩子生下来
But first I will push out this baby.
那就使把劲
Then push.
我来扶你 我扶你
I got you, got you.
你要折断它
You need to blow it.
别 行 行
No, don't, don't.
该死
Shit.
我得包扎伤口
I gotta pack the wound.
琪莉......
Kiri...
你没事吧？
Are you OK?
没事
Good.
使劲 酋长
Push, sheikh.
你得再加把劲
You have to one more push.
她出来了
She's coming.
接过你的孩子
Pick your child.
谢谢你
Thank you.
奈蒂莉......谢谢！
Neytiri...thank you!
她叫什么名字？
What is her name?
她叫布里尔
She...she is Brielle.
她很健壮
She's strong.
布里尔(意为上帝是我的力量)是个好名字
Brielle is good name.
你会保护她吗？
You will protect her?
我会
Yes.
爹 抱歉 我擅离职守了
Dad, I'm sorry I left my post.
没关系 儿子
It's okay, son.
可是......
But...
你已经向我证明了你的能力
You've proven yourself to me.
我说的是 你劝动了图鲲去反抗这件事
I mean getting the Tulkun to fight that.
就连”魅影骑士“都办不到
Even Toruk Makto couldn't do it.
而你做到了
And you did it.
我为你感到骄傲
I'm proud of you.
编号22 你们这边的伤亡情况如何？
Twenty two, how is your casualties?
全体人员
All right people,
请打起十二分精神
get ourselves together.
我们还有任务未完成
We've still got work to do.
你在逗我吗？
Seriously?
海湾里有一千亿美元在等着呢
There's a hundred billion dollars waiting in the cove.
而且没有什么能够阻挡我们
And nothing standing in our way.
啤酒我请客
Beers are on me.
你叫布里尔
Your name is Brielle.
你娘很强大 你以后也会和她一样强大
Your mother was powerful, you will be powerful too.
萨利夫人
Mrs. Sully.
不
No.
我们的战利品
It's spoils of the war.
爹
Dad.
看一下
Take a look.
不
No.
我现在需要你
I need you now.
在我身边
By my side.
当我的副手
I need my wingman.
好的
Okay.
咱们行动吧
Let's move out.
杰克
Jake.
我知道你在这里
I know you're out there.
我知道你能听得见
I know you can hear me.
瓦琅此刻正在热情款待你的妻子
Varang here is lighting up your wife pretty good.
不 娘亲
No, mom.
我令你进来 还有带上蜘蛛
Now I want you to come in and I want you to bring spider with,
我知道你收到了
and I konw you copy that.
谢谢 亲爱的
Thank you, baby.
把它拉起来 搞到里面 快 快
Pick it up, get in there, go, go.
我们被包围了
They're trapping us.
把那些辣椒及时藏起来
Let's get those peppers hidden in time.
几百米后 给我冲进去 进入射程范围
Hundred meters, give me in there, enter the range.
该死
Shit.
到那时 我们减速行驶 保持距离
At that point and hold slow even spacing.
鱼雷分队准备就绪
Sub teams torpedoes ready up.
鱼雷拦截准备
Torpedoes herming ready.
1至4号鱼雷武装
One to four torpedoes armed,
60米处
60 meters,
目标锁定
Aim be locked.
收网
Set it closed.
准备好 开火！
Stand by, fire!
图克 快看！
Tuk, Look!
别开火！
Hold it fire!
干嘛别开火？
Hold it fire for what?
我们得把这里情况弄清楚
You've to get the situation down here.
是伊娃觉醒了
It's Eywa arise.
它显灵了
It worked.
去吧 对付那些天空之人
Geht zu den Himmelsmenschen.
杀了他们！
Totet sie!
杀光他们！
Totet sie alle!
干得好！
Good job!
带我们离开这里
Get us out of here.
不 不
No, no.
快快快 撤离！
Go, go, go. Evacuate!
所有的船只撤回舰船！所有船只撤回舰船！
All boats back to the ship! All boats back to the ship!
好啊
Yeah.
没错 精灵
That's right, spirit.
噢 天啊
Oh, god.
带我们回基地
Get us back to the base.
不行啊 推进器停了
I can't, propulsion's down.
不
No.
啊......不.......
Ah...no...
打起精神
Get it up.
将军！
General!
恐怖的漩涡正把我们吸进去
Flux devils pulling us in.
放弃船只！
Aband ship!
Abandon ship!
跟紧我
Stay close.
安全
Clear.
好了
Okay.
所有人 放弃船只
Everybody, give up the ship.
朝他们开火！
Fire at them!
耶
Yes.
我需要火力掩护
I'll need cover fire, okay.
好的
Okay.
我会从左舷往左边走
I'll push left down the port side,
然后绕到他们的后面
and get around behind them.
有事立刻叫我
Get right on me.
看我指挥
Just watch me.
遵命
Yes sir.
别射伤我们的人
And don't shoot anyone you love.
去吧 去吧
Go, go.
上校 我是蜘蛛
Colonel, that's spider here.
别杀他
Don't kill him.
小子 你在哪里？
Where are you, boy?
快出来
Get out now.
好的 我这就出来
Great, I'll come out.
给我把他们通通干掉
Kill all them for me.
蜘蛛 听我说
Spider, you hear me.
我们的时间不多了
We're running out of time.
我来是为了做笔交易
I'm here to make a deal.
为了他们
That's for them.
Come with me, son.
跟我来 儿子
我向来牙齿当金使
I'm a man of my word.
我们现在答应你到此收手
We can resolve this here now.
放他们回家
Everybody goes home.
全体集合 我们撤离
Circle up, we're out of here.
图克
Tuk.
快走 图克
Come on, Tuk.
离我娘远点
Leave my mother alone.
混蛋！
Bastard！
走
Go.
快去找你娘
Go find your mother.
离开这艘船
Get off the ship.
抓紧 孩子
Hang on, child.
I'm here.
蜘蛛 这里
Spider, here.
杰克
Jake.
过来
Come on.
见鬼
Fuck.
杰克
Jake.
蜘蛛
Spider.
嘿
Hey.
洛阿克 走
Lo'ak, go.
快快快
Go, go, go.
驾
Ride.
该死
Shit.
杰克 杰克
Jake, jake.
我会杀了你 我发誓
I'll kill you, I swear.
你要杀你的亲爹吗？
You're gonna kill your own father?
你会死的
You'll die.
别逼我
Don't test me.
把它给我
Give me that.
你这个小杂碎！
You're a little bastard!
来吧
Come on.
杰克 快走
Jake, come on.
让我们继续打
Let us go on.
来吧
Come on.
哦 该死
Oh, shit.
杰克
Jake.
啊......
Ah...
孩子！
Child!
蜘蛛 不
Spider, no.
紧紧抓住
Hang on.
来啊
Come on.
拉我上来
Pull me up.
使劲
Come on.
你就不应该开枪打我的胳膊
You shouldn't to shot me in the arm.
我要放手了
I'll let you go.
那就来吧
Then do it.
老爹
Dad.
算你有点勇气 孩子
You have some courage, kid.
拉我上去
Pull me up.
握住我的手！
Take my hand!
杰克
Jake.
使劲
Come on.
我们没事了
We're fine now.
真的 我们差点就归西
So it's awkward.
现在该咋办？
Now what?
你要手牵手唱歌吗？
You're gonna hold hands and sing?
我刚学会了感知
I learned to see.
看来你还有选择的余地
You have a choice.
等等
Wait!
Wait.
等等
等等 等等
Wait, wait.
谢谢 这就是我的选择
Thanks, this is my choice.
爹 爹
Dad, dad.
我的杰克 坐吧
My Jake, sit.
字幕制作：月朗风清
光明终归会重现
The light always returns.
我们都与“万灵之母”连在一起
We all connect with the great mother.
她心中装着所有孩子
Who holds all her children in her heart.
新生命注入无限活力
New life keeps the energy flowing.
宛如世界的气息
Like the breath of the world.
我兄弟的声音被听到了
My brother's voice was heard.
他回归了他的大家族
He was accepted by the clan.
在灵魂世界里
In the spirit world,
我们呼唤先人的力量
we call upon the strength of the ancestors.
回到了昔日的世界 重见了久违的先人
All those who have walked the path before us.
来吧 猴男孩 快点
Come on, monkey boy. Come on.
来吧
Come on.
看到
See.
我看到你了
I see you.
兄弟
Bro.
这是怎么回事
This is going on.
见到你真高兴 老弟
I'm happy to see you, little bro.
嘿
Hey.
娘亲
Mom.
这是蜘蛛
This is spider.
我对你了如指掌
I've heard all about you.
淘气鬼
Troublemaker
这是你有生以来第一次体验到生命的存在
You are alive for the first time.
而你的灵魂将与伊娃同在
And your spirit will live in Eywa.
到永远
Forever.
现在 你是我们家族中的一员
You are one of us now.
你就是我们的族人
You are one of the people.
真的吗？
Really?
《阿凡达3：火与烬》